Isaac.
It is time... for Isaac.
Are you ready?
What's up, guys?
Oh, man.
Are you ready for this one, huh?
I'm ready.
Cheers!
Oh my god, it's Saturday.
Not quite Friday, but Saturday we'll have to do.
Are you all doing good?
First stream?
What's up, Armuri?
Welcome.
Can you hear me fine over the music?
I don't know if it's too loud.
I always have trouble testing this before the stream, so I rely on you guys.
Is it okay?
What's the screen supposed to be?
I have no idea.
All I know is that this is apparently the scribbles of the game developer in the early stages of when he was making the game.
I found it on Google Images.
I thought it looked cool.
I was gonna make a screen out of it.
I have no idea what any of that means.
It's not me.
I didn't write that, just so you know.
My handwriting is a lot better.
I know nothing about this game, guys.
Absolutely nothing.
Except that it's a roguelike, and it's very beloved, and people have thousands of hours in this game for some reason.
Yeah.
My real-life friend, Peter, he used to play this a lot.
He had, like, I think 500 hours or so.
And he's a guy that is very critical of games, you know.
He doesn't play games that much.
So yeah.
That's great.
We won't say nothing.
Good.
Yeah.
I mean, you're free to talk spoilers while I'm playing, of course.
Same rules as every other stream, you know.
I got all the DLCs, yes.
I was told to get everything, so I got everything.
I have everything that I can possibly get.
I have the developer next to me in the room as well for a commentary.
He decided to join me on this one.
I told you I would get everything.
I'm kidding about that one.
But besides that, I have everything.
Same procedure as every year.
Exactly.
I'm not a true Oliver fan.
I only watched game I'm interested in and I was waiting for Isaac.
That's totally cool, though.
That's the deal with variety channels, right?
I mean, not the same way.
I also only watch let's plays of games I have played and I'm interested in, right?
What's Jackie up to?
I don't know.
Let me check.
Oh, she's sleeping.
I mean, cats are comatose most of the day.
So I'm not really surprised.
All I have to do is look behind me and I can see her.
By the way, I'm trying out something new today with the chats or the overlay chat.
I'm no longer reliant on stream elements because I fucking hate their interface.
It is impossible to customize anything.
So this is all custom HTML now.
Home cooked, baby.
So there may be some bugs.
Let me know after the stream and we will try and fix those for next time.
If there's anything wrong, maybe an emote isn't working or something.
A badge is maybe not working.
I don't know.
Yeah.
I was doing a bunch of testing earlier today just to make sure, but I may have, you know, missed some outliers.
The chat is much more readable in game.
Don't worry.
This is just the start screen.
I thought it looked cool with the scribbles, you know?
But yeah.
Chat looks so yummy, does it?
I guess so.
I kind of want to eat it.
When is the blind chess playthrough coming?
There's already a couple episodes of the blind chess playthrough.
It's on my second channel.
It's called More Oliver.
It sounds like I'm joking, but I'm not.
Yeah, you can go subscribe to that one.
Subscribe to my second channel, by the way.
Yeah.
It did look cool.
At first I thought that you had written one of the chat messages.
I mean, I had earlier, like three hours ago.
I was spamming my own chat with all kinds of messages just to test, you know?
Maybe you saw one of those.
Giving hidden information about difficulties.
Yeah, just don't tell me anything.
Unless it's like something about, you know, oh, you should totally enable this setting in the menus, otherwise you'll get lags.
Or, you know, something very obvious that I should have tweaked, you know?
The only thing I've touched in this game is the music levels.
So I don't know if there's anything I need to be changing in the menu.
Controller in this game gives you much more precision.
I'm gonna go with keyboard because I've been burned by controller in Hollow Knight Silksong.
Not again.
I am now a keyboard supremacist.
Down with controllers.
Keyboards rise up.
If it's really bad on keyboard, I'll switch over to controller.
We'll see how it feels.
Have you heard of the creator's new game, New Genix?
I have not heard.
Oh, actually, I have heard of that.
But I don't know anything about it, but I've heard the name.
It just came out of something, right?
It's very popular.
Everyone's playing that.
I'm like, here we go.
Binding of Isaac.
The first time I heard about Binding of Isaac, I was watching a man.
You know, playing.
What game was that?
The Last of Us.
And in the beginning of the game, there's a tutorial on how to heal yourself.
And you're playing as Joel, right?
So he's healing himself, banishing himself up.
And then he says the Binding of Joel.
And for some reason, that was so hilarious because he was talking about the Binding of Isaac right before then.
And I don't know, that just stuck with my mind, you know?
So that's all I thought about when I thought of Binding of Isaac for all this time.
But now I know it's like a top-down 2D shooter, rogue-like type game.
Yeah.
Cool story.
I know.
I can tell it again.
Want to hear it again?
I'm here all night.
No, I'm kidding.
How about we play the game?
Yeah.
The Binding of Joel.
I just, I love man.
I kind of miss man.
He used to stream a lot more.
Okay.
Let's do this.
Let's hope this works.
By the way, there was a cutscene when I started the game.
I will ask you guys this.
Do I need to restart the game to see the cutscene?
Or will that cutscene come again?
Because I didn't watch it.
I just skipped through it to get to the main menu.
Wait, I forgot what I said.
So is it gonna come again or is it not gonna come again?
Oh, I have to restart.
Okay, okay.
Hold on.
I'll do it because I want to watch it.
One sec.
Okay, let me get this done.
Oh, I need to switch the scene as well.
Of course, you can see this.
There we go.
A game by Nicholas.
Isaac and his mother lived alone in a small house on a hill.
Isaac kept to himself, drawing pictures and playing with his toys as his mom watched Christian broadcasts on the television.
What life was simple and they were both happy.
That was until the day Isaac's mom heard a voice from above.
Your son has become corrupted by sin.
He needs to be saved.
I will do my best to save him, my lord.
Isaac's mother replied rushing into Isaac's room, removing all that was evil from his life.
Again, the voice called to her.
Isaac's soul is still corrupt.
He needs to be cut off from all that is evil in this world and confess his sins.
I will follow your instructions, lord.
I have faith in thee.
Isaac's mother replied as she locked Isaac in his room away from the evils of the world.
One last time, Isaac's mom heard the voice of God calling to her.
You've done as I've asked, but I still question your devotion to me to prove your faith.
I will ask one more thing of you.
Yes, lord, anything, Isaac's mother begged.
To prove your love and devotion, I require a sacrifice.
Your son, Isaac, will be this sacrifice.
Holy shit.
Go into his room and end his life as an offering to me to prove you love me above all else.
Grabbing a butcher's knife from the kitchen, Isaac watching through a crack in his door trembled in fear, scrambling around his room to find a hiding place.
He noticed a trap door to the basement hidden under his rug.
Without hesitation, he flung open the hatch just as his mother burst through his door and threw himself down into the unknown depths below.
Damn, dude, that is freaking dark.
What the hell?
I was not expecting that.
That turned dark really quick.
Oh, man, imagine that.
It's probably not even far from the truth in some cases.
I mean, this has probably happened, you know?
Someone went nuts because of some religious belief and felt like they had to murder their child?
Oh, my God.
No.
Oh, my goodness.
That is horrible.
Oh, man.
Hold on a minute.
The music or the sound was a little low there.
I'm going to check with you guys one sec.
Okay.
Is this still okay?
Should I turn music or something up here?
Turn it up halfway.
Dude, it's already so loud in my ears.
Okay, hold on.
I can I can fix it for you.
Is
that better?
I don't know how it is when I play.
Okay, I'm going to check in with you guys in like half an hour, okay?
And we'll see how the sound is.
Okay, I'm back in.
Let's do this online.
Uh, I don't know about that.
New run.
Who am I?
I can't get over that intro, though.
Isaac.
Oh, you can have multiple characters.
Magdalene, Kane, Judas, Eve, Samson, Esaisal, Lazarus.
Oh, I thought I thought you were going to play as a treasure chest for a second, but it's locked.
Okay.
Eulith?
I don't know what that means.
Apollyon, Bethany, Jacob.
Jacob.
Let's go.
Press tab to input a seed.
Oh, wait, this is difficult to slider.
Wait, what?
I guess I'm just going to go with normal.
Okay, basement one.
Oh, that oh, that is weird.
Bomb E.
Okay, item on space.
I like the music.
Um, oh, that's weird.
I have to, like, actually aim or shoot in the direction I want.
Oh, I was hoping I could aim with my mouse or something.
Doesn't seem to be the case.
Wait, maybe I can actually do that.
Options.
Change controller.
I don't know.
I don't think so.
Okay, I'm just going to go.
Fuck it.
What's this?
Okay, I can't fall into hold.
That's good.
I don't understand what is happening in this game.
What is that?
I took damage, but I got money.
I don't know what's happening.
I can go through here now.
Oh, here we go.
Oh, god.
Oh, wait, this is not going to be like a bullet hell game, is it?
I'm terrible at that stuff.
Oh, no.
Oh, shit.
I'm at one HP, dude.
This is not good.
I got money and a key.
Um, there's a bomb here.
Wait, how was the bomb?
E.
Why can't I place a bomb?
Oh, I don't have any bombs.
Okay.
Why can I not pick this bomb up?
Is there like a keybind for that?
Hold on a minute.
I need to check something real quick.
Change controller?
No.
Oh, maybe I can't rebind or see my keybinds.
Okay.
Okay, that's fine.
Whatever.
Uh, I don't know how to get to these.
What's that?
Large sit.
It's just, it's like, okay.
It's, he has a large sit on his face.
I didn't even see what it said.
Crap shoot or something.
Wait, what is, oh.
Oh, no, it's popping.
And there's cyst fluid on the floor.
Oh,
what the hell is going, why?
I don't know what's happening.
But I'm excited nonetheless.
There's also a bomb embedded in that rock.
I have one key.
I kind of want to open one of these chests with that.
I can go, oh, I have a map in the top right too.
What's up, guys?
Dude, I'm gonna, I'm gonna fucking nail this game.
This is like, fucking easy.
Are you kidding me?
I'm not gonna take any damage anymore.
What's this?
I got a, I don't know, two billion balls.
I'm shooting poop.
There sits some poop.
This is not a good start.
Um, okay, I can go left or I can go down.
I'm gonna go left.
Oh, god, what the hell?
Dude, they're full of crying blood.
I just noticed I'm crying.
Hey, guys.
Oh, I released them now.
Uh-oh.
Oh, they're shooting stuff at me.
Okay.
Well, I'm gonna turn it up a little bit.
I want to hear this music a little more.
There we go.
I'm gonna check with you guys in like 20 minutes, okay?
And we'll see how it is.
Oh, god.
Okay.
Oh, I have half a heart left.
Oh, I'm in deep shit.
This ain't good.
Are you guys gonna shoot stuff at me?
They are.
Oh,
1967 is when Isaac died, apparently.
Dear diary, that's me.
Today I died.
I was killed by this thing.
I don't know what that is.
A spit squid.
In some basement.
I leave all that I own to my cat, Guppy.
What does that say?
Cock stuff?
Cook stuff?
Cool stuff?
I think.
Goodbye, cruel world.
XOXO, Isaac.
Wow, that was... First death doesn't count, right?
Ooh, look at that door.
That doesn't look good.
Let's see.
I lost HP.
Guppy's color, eternal life.
It's my cat's color, yay!
Wait, what do you mean eternal?
Wait, am I wearing a diaper?
Why does it look like that?
Oh, I take damage both ways.
Oh!
What's up, baddie?
What's going on?
Oh, it's not even that hard.
These little fuckers killed me last time, I think.
Healing.
Okay, uh, we got a golden door, a brown door, and a light brown door.
I have a feeling this is a boss.
I'm gonna go this way.
What's up, guys?
Oh, that guy has an extra eye!
I mean, one less eye.
Oh, god.
Dude, the game is super simple, and it's the magician.
I didn't have any time to read that at all.
I'm a magician now.
Oh, wait, it's in the bottom right, too.
Oh!
Oh, I can only have one of them.
May you... Hold on.
Question mark, may you never miss your goal.
That's good, though, right?
Oh, wait, what is that?
That is a boss.
We're not going in there.
Uh, what's this?
Oh, it's like a shop room!
Five cents, ten cents.
How much do I have?
Zero.
I got no... Who's that?
Someone's hanging from the ceiling.
Dude, I like this music.
Donation?
Uh, I don't... I don't... I can't buy anything.
Let's go in here.
Okay, I have a feeling this is a trap.
I picked this up.
Something's gonna happen.
Nancy bombs.
I can't read it in time.
It said something about random blasts.
Oh!
Shoot the fu... Oh!
Hey!
There you go!
I traded HP for money.
Oh, I think that counted as five.
I have seven now.
I should have gone in here before I went to the other room.
Healing!
Okay, what about this rock?
Can I blow it up?
Oh, it's like Bomberman!
Dude, I love that!
I love Bomberman!
What are these things?
I don't understand what's happening.
I guess I'm making progress, right?
What is that on the map up there?
Oh, that's the room where I took damage.
Let's not go that way.
Oh, I guess we have to go in here.
Isaac versus Larry Jr. Oh, shit.
They're pooping!
Oh my god.
Shoot the poop.
Dude, I'm terrible at these types of games where there's so much stuff happening.
Oh my god!
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
I lured them into a corner.
Yeah, come here, guys.
You ain't got nothing on me.
Oh, crap.
I'm actually dying.
I'm dying.
I got him!
One left.
We can't fuck this up now.
This is crucial.
Man, my projectiles are so slow.
Yeah!
It's a picture of torn photo tears plus shot speed up.
Oh my god, I'm crying even more.
Is that because I found a photo of me in the past when I was happy, maybe?
And now I'm even more sad?
So, wait, our mom wants to kill us because, you know, God told her to.
And then we escaped into the basement through a trapdoor.
And we are just wandering through these halls down here in the basement, freaking crying, because our mom wants to kill us.
That is actually so horrific.
Am I shooting tears?
Because he's crying.
Oh my god.
Oh, and we're going deeper.
Oh, no.
What?
What the fuck was that?
Was that my mom's wording out of her tits on me?
I don't know what I just looked at.
I'm just describing it.
What was that?
Oh, god.
We got a little angry fly thingy.
Dude, what is it with these things that I can't... bomb?
Oh, shit!
There's a ghost!
I can't hit it.
Ah!
No, thanks.
Oh, god.
Wait, can I bomb these guys?
Hey!
Oh, that's super effective!
That's the way to do it.
Oh, there's a door with a key on it.
Or keyhole.
Blood of the Martyr.
Damage up.
Good.
More damage for me.
No more doors down there.
Okay, we got a bunch of stuff.
Oh, he's shooting, I don't know, tar at me.
He's shooting tar?
I'm shooting tear.
Shoot the little guys first.
Okay, he's not actually aiming for me.
It's just diagonal shots.
Oh, I'm full on HP!
Dude, I'm owning it.
Hello?
I'm also kind of rich right now.
There's a shop up here.
You know what?
Let's wait with that.
I'm already going to optimize the shit out of this game.
I don't need to go in there yet.
I can always come back, right?
I wish I could somehow zoom on that.
What is that on the floor?
Why is my screen shaking?
Okay, okay.
It's just a camera readjusting.
Hey guys, what's going on?
It's Isaac.
I'm here to rock your world.
Kill you with my sadness.
I'm gonna tell you the saddest story of all time.
Oh wait, that's a boss.
Hold on now.
Let's go up here.
Oh, I can't.
Oh, it needs a key.
Shit, okay.
Well, all right.
Isaac versus Dingle?
That's a turd.
Maybe I killed the small turds first.
Playing music?
Oh no, I can't dodge it.
Okay, we just... as soon as he does that, we move.
Oh my gosh.
You can probably get like movement speed upgrades or something later.
This guy's hella... whoa, I'm about to say easy.
Okay, okay, okay.
Poops got hands.
Surprisingly.
Oh, I don't have infinite range either.
Calm down.
Okay, he's gonna... oh, I got hit by that.
Oh, sick dodge.
Sick dodge.
Always gonna do that now, yeah.
Let's just keep moving.
Beautiful.
Oh, I don't have infinite range at all.
It's sort of...
I had no time to read that.
Glass eye, damage plus lock up.
Okay.
Dude, I wish I could somehow read the stuff that comes on screen.
Oh, glass... dude, I love the fact that my character is wearing the stuff I find.
That's kind of cool.
I have a glass eye now.
It's a waterfall of tears coming out of that eye.
Okay.
Going deeper.
What am I gonna find in the...
People are making fun of Isaac when he's on the toilet.
Acting as if they don't take a shit, huh?
Everyone poops, dude.
Why are you making fun of him for that?
That doesn't make any sense at all.
At least Isaac is less full of shit, you know?
Those guys are probably full of it.
You can actually kind of... you see this?
You can sort of angle the shot a little bit.
I was trying to hold up and right at the same time, but it just alternates.
Pushpin, piercing shots.
Oh, that sounds really good.
That sounds really good.
Also, I don't understand what this X1 question mark means on my health.
Question mark?
I don't want question mark.
Man, you never miss your goal.
I like that one.
I don't want to miss any goals.
I want to be on point, you know?
What's with these... oh wait, is there a puzzle here?
Someone took a bite out of this one, that one, this one, some of them they didn't.
Let me blow them up.
Mushroom juice!
Okay, let me see the piercing.
Come here.
Is that a battery?
Why can't I pick that up?
I don't know why I can't pick that up.
I wonder how much of this is randomly generated.
It's probably a lot, right?
Feels like the type of game where most of it would be RNG.
Oh, Jesus!
Okay, they don't have a lot of range though.
What's up, dude?
Whoa!
Dude, these guys are crazy.
Oh, two of them here.
I'm killing them.
Nice!
Okay, that wasn't too bad, actually.
I expected that to be...
Or to go a lot worse than it did.
So I can go right on and go down.
Oh, wait, I can also go here.
Wait, what?
Oh, I was there already.
Okay.
Oh, you can actually see on the map that the battery thingy is in here right now.
For later, if I need to remember.
But I can't pick it up, so I don't really know what's going on with that.
Who are you?
Okay, we got a key.
So, wait, there's a treasure chest here, though.
I can't get across.
I can somehow push it.
Whoa!
I have a key!
I could go down here.
And what is this?
Looks like it's closed off.
Oh, we got bad thingies!
They're gonna suck my blood.
I don't like that.
Nice!
One down.
Hey, that wasn't too bad!
Another key?
Gambling!
I'm not winning.
Hey!
Fuck yeah, dude!
I can just keep doing this?
What?
It's probably like 10 tries or something, right?
Hey!
What the fuck?
That's sick!
Oh, I don't need it.
Actually, I did need it.
Nice!
Oh, I... Oh!
Oh, wait, I see now.
Okay, I'm using my money on this.
That's fine.
I'm gonna go down here.
What's that?
If I step on that, I'm gonna take damage.
BOMB!
Jesus Christ!
It's like a random bomb.
Number one, tears up plus range down.
Oh, so it's like close range, but deadly.
Got it.
Okay, interesting.
Well, I guess it's boss time.
Wait, there's also a room back here.
This one I didn't explore yet.
You!
Whoa.
I think I prefer to have more range.
Being close is scary.
I don't like being close.
I think the magician or whatever that is, it's like a passive buff I just have.
For the rest of the run or something.
Um, let's go up to the boss.
Okay.
Oh, man.
I spent all my money on this and there was a money room here.
I just wasted a key.
I didn't mean to enter.
What a freaking Minecraft pig?
Doesn't that look like a Minecraft pickaxe?
Pixelated and shit?
Isaac versus fistula?
I don't like that sound.
Name of that.
Okay, he's gonna... oh.
Okay, I was expecting something, not that.
No problem.
No problem for Isaac, though.
Oh, Jesus.
Kill the smaller ones first, I guess.
We don't wanna have too many small ones at the same time.
Jesus.
Oh my god.
Oh my god!
We're almost dead.
It's over.
Wow.
A baby bottle.
Tropicamide.
I didn't get to read it.
Dude, why is this on screen for like 0.25 seconds?
I don't have any time to read anything.
What's this?
We're crying?
Because we're imagining ourselves crying?
Oh my god, Isaac, what the fuck is wrong with you?
Look at his eyes.
Is that the drug we just took?
What the fuck?
That ain't good.
Uh-oh.
Oh no.
Oh, they explode when they die.
I'm about to die here.
It's over.
Wow.
Oh, shit.
I got blown up.
I got blown up and killed by this thing in some cave.
Ugly, plus.
I got some cool stuff.
Oh man.
Okay, hold on, hold on.
Let me check with you guys real quick.
How has the audio been, okay?
Is everything working as it should?
Are we doing fine?
What's up?
Audio is good?
Is the music too loud though?
Because it's kind of loud in my ears, but I want it to be loud, right?
Um...
Wait, what?
Audio good.
A little loud.
Please use controller?
No.
I'm doing fine with the keyboard.
What do you mean?
Settings has HUD, which is good.
Oh, can I change the duration?
For the thing?
Because I can't get to read it in time.
Pop-ups.
Oh, that's good.
I don't know what active cam is.
Extra HUD?
Normal.
Should I enable these?
What should I have on here?
Guys, can I make it so that I can actually read the stuff I pick up?
Because it automatically disappears within like half a second.
There is no time to read it.
Everything on?
Okay.
Bullet disability.
Oh, put that on high.
Filter.
Ugh.
Okay, let's just try this.
Oh, okay.
Whoa.
Okay, maybe that's... is that too much?
There was another option.
I don't know what any of that means.
This almost feels like the Minecraft version of having the debug menu on.
Mini?
Didn't change anything.
All right, whatever.
Okay, let's just go.
Okay, this is kind of fun.
I like it.
Oh God, we got vampire thingies.
Wait, is that me?
It's another version of me that I'm killing.
Dude, I'm gonna kill it now.
I understand how the game works now.
Money?
The Ludo... yeah, I can't... I don't have time to read it.
Huh?
Wait, what?
Oh, I'm controlling like a... I'm controlling an orb.
And this is gonna damage enemies?
That's fucking awesome.
What the hell, bro?
Mind control, mind control.
Okay, someone said press space.
I can't do anything.
Okay, well, I'm gonna ask you guys.
Hold on, maybe... can I... why can I not see the freaking controls in the game?
Like, why can I not just see my controls?
It's so weird.
Jacob plus Esau controls classic.
Guys, can I see my controls somehow?
I'm gonna hold tab.
Controls are in the menu, which is a bit... I am in the menu.
Oh, you mean the main menu?
Oh, press Q.
Oh, okay.
Hold on.
Tab?
Oh, oh, okay.
So I get to see the map.
Okay, well, whatever.
I'm fine for now.
I got locked down, which is not good, I guess.
I guess luck is gonna determine whether or not you're gonna find good items or bad items, because I just found a bad item.
Dude, this is so cool the way I'm controlling this freaking orb.
Like, what the hell?
That's actually really cool.
So are they gonna have a lot of those types of items that just change the game or something?
This is really different.
Can I just hover it and it will... Oh, okay.
Wait, that's a boss.
I don't want to go in there yet.
That's crazy.
There's a shop here, but I don't have any money.
So this is actually a bad idea.
There's also room here.
Scanning with my orb.
Scanning with the orb.
Oh, I can see the item on the right side.
I see now.
Ah, okay.
That's cool.
So wait a minute.
Let me look at the stats on the left.
I have speed one.
I'm gonna guess attack speed 2.7, attack damage 3.5, range 6.5.
I don't know what that next one is.
Luck minus one, but that's a three leaf clover.
I don't know what the bottom two are, though.
Kind of gravestone and a demon.
Dude, I love the music and it's actually so cool.
It gets me in the mood, you know.
It gets the blood pumping here.
Isaac versus Gemini.
Oh, so it's actually different every time.
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
Oh, there's two of them.
Ah, this is so weird.
I need to use both sides of my brain for this one.
I can't control both at the same time.
Just hover over him.
Hover!
Like, maybe kill the small guy first.
Kill him!
Okay, I'm gonna fucking chute this guy.
Okay, he's down, he's down!
Stay mad, bro.
Okay, I don't have a lot of speed on the orb, though.
Oh, he's exhausted now.
Good night, sir!
The belt!
Speed up!
Oh, yeah!
Wait, why does a belt give me speed?
How does that make any sense?
What?
A belt?
Maybe because you don't have to pull up your pants as much anymore when you're walking, probably.
Okay, let's go.
Wait, I'm entering something with a timer on it.
Oh, man!
Isaac!
Try to give flowers and then someone pull his pants down.
Looks like the unlockiest guy in the world.
Oh, shit, I'm gonna... Okay, stay back here.
Just fucking smash everything.
Yeah!
Dude, this is so cool!
I like it.
I got a key.
Oh my god, we're rich!
13 coins!
Take out the fires.
What about this here?
This doesn't do anything.
I wonder if I can upgrade the amount of hearts I have, because I don't have enough.
Oh!
Okay, I was about to say they gotta do something other than that.
Oh, it's too fast!
I gotta... I'm gonna stay in the center.
There we go.
Yeah!
Can I somehow remotely fucking blast my orb or something?
Oh, shit, okay.
I thought maybe I could place the bomb where this guy was now.
Ooh, there's little disgusting worms underneath the rocks.
I don't like... Oh, there's a boss.
I don't think I should go there yet.
We're gonna explore every room before the boss.
Become as strong as we can.
Like... Oh, wait, I see how I'm gonna get to that now.
I need to blow these rocks away to get in there.
Oh, shit.
I'm in trouble!
Kill the little guy.
Dude, I'm actually kind of killing it.
Hello?
Easy game.
Wait, did he have a force field?
I feel like he was pushing my orb, if you know what I mean.
Okay, get in here.
Oh, this is a trap.
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
No?
Oh, shit.
What is that?
Is that a gopher?
I killed him.
No problem.
Uh, pieces of meat.
Okay, man.
Uh-oh.
What the hell is that?
Oh, look at this!
Long range sniping!
Dude, this is broken as hell!
Oh, yeah!
Wait, what is this?
Wait, is this gonna be... I donate blood and I get money or something?
Hold on, I think that's exactly what that is.
I'm not gonna do it.
I'm gonna wait a little bit, until I find a heart.
I'm playing this so optimally, even though I don't understand what's happening.
Nice.
Take out the fires.
I guess fires are bad.
Although, I would think in a dank cave like this, you would like a fire, no?
Dude, I'm so rich!
Speaking of rich!
Okay, we can buy a purple box.
Fuck!
I can't buy the box now!
Well, I'm just gonna...
I'm donating everything.
Maybe when I reach a certain threshold, something good happens.
A blue map has appeared and I didn't get to read the rest.
Thank you, game.
They really need to change that.
Like, you have no time to read that shit.
Are you kidding me?
Like, it pops up and I'm like, whoa, what's happening?
And then it's gone before I even realize it, you know?
That's like a crazy oversight.
Are you kidding me?
Well, all my money has been donated and now I have a map.
But I already had a map, so I'm confused.
Basement 2...
Okay, boss room is on the left.
Uh, we could go in here, but then we lose HP.
Where's my orb?
Oh, can I go through with this?
No, okay.
Uh, I guess I'm gonna go down here.
What's that?
Stitches, bait and switch.
Wait, what is happening?
I have two of these now.
I don't know what's happening.
Uh, can you go in there?
I'm gonna go in.
Oh god.
Shit!
Oh my god, this is so weird!
Okay, okay.
I guess it's like double damage or something right now, because I got two minions.
That was it?
That was a horrible room!
Oh no, wait, wait, wait, wait, I need to somehow...
It looks like there's half a heart in one of the rooms.
If I get that... No, I need money.
Wait, what is this stuff in here?
Oh, I can't buy this.
No.
That's too... Why did I donate all my money?!
That was a horrible idea.
Dude, what if I actually get HP from this, instead of donating?
This could actually help me.
But it's kind of risky to do, because I'm at one HP.
I'm not gonna do it.
It's too risky.
That's a heart!
Fuck yeah.
Wait, you know what?
I'm gonna try and blow some shit up here.
Uh, I have bombs.
Maybe there's stuff in the pots.
A spider!
Okay, I'm gonna blow up here.
Oh wait, I have no more bombs!
Oh no.
Okay, it's time for a boss.
Stay safe and use this at range.
Oh, it's Dingle!
Easy.
It's over.
I'm dead.
Okay, okay, not bad.
Nice.
He's gonna charge me.
Good.
Don't die now.
Yeah, dude!
I killed him!
I'm the best.
Wait, why can't I kill this thing down here?
Wait, is only one of these dealing damage?
Caddo, nine tails, shots.
Okay, I guess I can see what I got.
I got speed and damage?
I'm not sure.
Wait, what?
I'm so confused.
So, it's only the orb that does damage.
What does the other one do that I have?
It was called bait and switch.
That could both be good or bad, I guess.
Money.
Oh, you know what?
We can go back and heal.
I'm gonna play so optimally right now.
You're probably super impressed by this gameplay right here, because this is crazy smart.
We're going back here, and we're gonna go inside this room.
Here, and by this heart.
Look at that.
Beautiful.
You know what?
I have one left.
Fuck it.
Have a beer on me.
Whoever you are.
Spooky guy who runs the shop in the middle of the basement underneath my house.
We go down to the next level now.
Okay, let's go.
Level three.
Was that mom?
Dude, mom is so cruel.
What the fuck?
Wait, something just said 100% plus in the bottom left.
Demon mode activated.
100% demon mode right now.
What the... Wait, they're not taking any damage.
Oh, they can't die.
There's a switch.
Wow, okay.
Cool.
Oh, that turned them off.
Okay.
Um, let's go up here.
What is that?
That's a vacuum cleaner.
Technology.
Laser tears.
What is happening?
Dude, this is so cool the way the items actually change everything.
I really dig that concept.
Wait, everything.
Whoa!
Dude, that is crazy good.
I like that.
The vacuum is insane.
Look at the way I...
Dude, I feel like I'm gonna end up dying at the end of this.
I mean, I am, but you know what I mean.
But look at me.
I'm like totally malformed now.
This is looking like something out of cyberpunk.
Should I... Maybe I should keep these guys sort of stacked, my two minions here.
Ah, but wait a minute.
One of them moves faster than the other, so we can't.
That's awkward.
Oh, it's only from the border.
Okay, I thought it was within the circle.
I see, I see.
Okay.
Can I... I cannot fall in the holes.
Uh, right.
Get fucked!
Dude, that's crazy good.
That's a blue one!
What does that mean?
Oh, they're not gonna do anything to me.
Oh, that's gonna deal damage to me.
I don't know if I wanna do that.
Let's wait.
We're playing it.
Oh, look at this.
Oh my god!
Dude, the laser is crazy!
Fucking demolition over here.
How do I... blow it up!
I want this.
I don't know what just happened.
I found pills and ate... Oh, they're pills.
Explosive.
Diarrhea?
What the fuck?
You should not have eaten those pills, Isaac.
What are you doing?
Here, have a beer on me.
That's 18.
That's 18, baby.
Let's see what's down here.
Okay, we killed things.
Wow, there's so many projectiles.
I can't see what's happening.
I'm almost dead here.
Wait, they're gonna shoot?
Yeah, okay.
Uh, there's no way I'm making this.
How will I get there?
Impossible.
Wow, gaming!
Oh, wait, there's another button!
I'm in danger.
Go down here.
Let's fucking go.
Kill him!
Before they kill me!
We got him, we got him.
Oh, no, that's a boss!
I can't!
We don't have any HP.
Oh, wait, there's multiple rooms still.
Hold on, I gotta go back.
We gotta look for HP!
Look for that HP.
There's a room up here.
Here.
Key.
And another room.
But how do I... Yo, even if I blow up these rocks, I can't get in here.
Oh, TNT.
Oh, cool.
Except I can't get in the center there.
Oh, I can, okay.
Well, I have some money now, but I forgot what the storekeeper had for me.
Oh, let's see here.
I don't think I could buy HP down there.
We're just gonna have to boss it.
Going in here is gonna kill us, though.
Is that pee on the floor?
God damn, Isaac, you're in bad shape.
You don't want to make your mom even more mad.
Okay, let's do it.
Wish me luck.
What the fuck is that?
It's Gertie!
Disgusting shit.
Kill the little ass.
He's gonna do something here.
We got him?
That's an enemy!
I thought it was a tomato!
Synth oil, damage plus range up.
That's good.
Except range?
What do you mean?
I have infinite range.
Hello.
How's that gonna help me?
Level four.
We got the boob squirts.
I'm not sure what's happening there, but sure.
Whoa!
Two keys needed for this one!
And we got two keys back!
Hello, this is the craziest room of all time!
Wait, what if there's like invisible walls?
Imagine that.
Or not illusory walls, you know what I mean.
Shit!
How do I damage you?
Oh, okay, so it's only when he pops up.
By the way, is my central part also doing damage?
I'm not quite sure.
I feel like the edge does for sure, but the central part?
Not so sure.
Okay, let's go this way.
Gambling!
Oh, but wait!
This may be a bad idea.
Let's not do it yet.
What is that?
Smart fly.
Revenge fly?
Nice!
Like a little minion.
It's gonna protect me, I guess.
Okay, uh, I really... okay.
I'm not gonna gamble.
What?!
Portal... portable slot!
Gamble 24-7?
Wait, what am I doing?
Oh!
I see, I see, I see!
Okay, so I was gambling there.
I used all my money.
I didn't mean to.
Wait, something died.
Hey, come out!
Laser-designated target acquired.
Money backs!
Uh, no wait, question mark backs.
Hmm.
But I can't even get there.
If I blow up this rock, I can't get in there.
I don't know what's happening with that.
Yeah, the central... the center does not do anything.
It's only the edge that does damage here.
That's not a green tomato.
That's a disgusting egg.
You don't want that.
Whoa!
Dude, just having infinite rage is kind of crazy!
I just did something!
Piano melody just played.
That means I did a secret.
Kill them all.
Annihilated!
Hello!
You ain't got nothing on?
Oh, why can't I... is this guy immune?
Is he gonna pop up or something?
Maybe if I get close, I'm not sure.
Kill them all.
Okay, wait, there's a door here that's closed.
Hey, now he popped up!
Hey, I'm here!
Come on!
Do your thing!
Wait, what?
Oh, maybe I need to not damage him for a while, and then he comes up?
He sees me now.
Hello!
Okay, and then he popped... okay, I see, I see.
So we gotta not seem threatening, and then we go down.
There we go.
Okay, got it.
Bombs!
Sweet.
Oh, Jesus.
Oh, I see.
Yo, this is kind of cool.
How do I get there?
I can go left or down.
I mean, right or down.
Let's go right.
Oh, shit.
Everything just dies.
It's awesome.
This is a much better run than the last one.
Wait, what?
Minus 64% on demon.
I don't know what that means.
Oh, what?
Oh, that's the boss room.
There is a money room we didn't enter.
Why didn't we enter that?
Let me go back.
I need to see.
What the hell is up?
Wow!
Wait, I can't go back here.
I need to follow them, I think.
It's the only way out.
Down here.
Okay, do I... Oh, I don't have any money, never mind.
I was about to say, what do I choose?
With my infinite money, but I don't have anything.
And then we go down like this.
Boss time!
Who's it gonna be?
It's gonna be Gertie Jr. Okay, why are all these bosses so disgustingly ugly?
Wow.
Bro, I'm fucking nailing this boss!
Lil' Chubby?
Are you serious?
Mom's coin purse.
What's all this?
It's pills!
Mom is an addict!
Oh, we don't know what they do.
That's good.
Tears up?
I guess that's... Wait a minute.
That means I'm crying more.
That's...
I think it's good, because it's my attack, right?
I can see forever.
What?
Health up.
Oh my god!
Yeah!
That's dope!
I like that one.
Level five!
Wait, what happened there?
I couldn't quite decipher what that movie was about.
Why is there a timer on my screen now?
Why is there a timer?
Oh, we gotta hurry.
We have to hurry!
Things are happening.
I don't even know what's happening.
It's, uh, this way.
Why's my map?
Oh.
Oh, the map was open!
I see.
Oh.
Lead pencil.
He's a bleeder.
Huh?
I don't know what that means.
Kill them all!
Fucking smash him.
Oh, that's not a tomato.
Wait, what?
Oh, he's a bleeder?
So wait, what's happening?
I'm bleeding things out of my body, I guess.
Kill these guys.
There's a key in the center that I can't possibly get to.
I haven't figured out how to actually get those things.
I do have three bombs?
I could destroy this, should I?
That did nothing.
Surprise.
Whoa.
Oh!
I see.
Okay, we gotta be... No, wait, I can't get there.
The slight acceleration in the movement makes it hard to do this precise, but I guess that's the point.
Okay.
Uh, we can use a key here.
We have a lot of keys.
Isaac versus Greed?
Boom!
Whoever you are, you're dead.
Steam sale 50% off?
Yo, that's actually kind of dope.
There's also a spring steam sale right now, actually.
Oh, wow.
Bro, I don't even know what's happening.
I feel like I'm super powerful.
Somehow, some way.
Wow.
I don't even know what happened.
Something died.
Yeah, okay.
Boss time.
Loki.
That's a demon.
Oh, we got things moving on the arena.
Ah!
Okay, okay.
I got a blue heart.
A better heart.
Box, it's stuff.
Oh.
Red patch, your rage grows.
And a pill with dots on it.
Range down.
Oh, shit.
The high priestess.
Did it say mom is waiting for you?
Oh, I gambled.
Hey!
I'm getting rich!
Wait, I can do range down again?
Why would I do that?
Ah, wait.
Dude, gambling is crazy.
I love gamble.
We're reaching a boss.
We're inside a treasure chest.
And we can't breathe.
That's horrible.
Depths too.
Okay.
Oh, Jesus.
Are these guys gonna come up here?
Wait, what?
Oh, they're inactive now because I killed the enemies, I guess.
Wait, we have this red patch in the bottom left, but I don't know what it means.
What did I just do?
What the fuck did I just do?
What the fuck?
I didn't take any damage.
Oh, I didn't take any damage at all.
Okay, you're dead.
Holy shit.
Um, sure.
Oh, wait, there's a room here.
Wow.
Come here, you purple gangster.
Let's go.
Wait, wait, wait.
What's this?
Why is it, uh, bloody?
That doesn't sound good.
I don't know why it's bloody.
Oh, wait.
If I destroy the purple fire, something bad happens.
I predicted, so I'm gonna push these.
It's blue now.
Oh, I can't distinguish it.
Okay, I don't think I quite understood what was going on here.
I mean, what the fuck is happening?
Oh, this is some demonic shit.
Look at this circle here.
They were summoning evil, for sure.
I'm gonna go this way.
Stay at range.
Just sit back here.
We don't need to move.
Ah!
Ew.
There we go.
Money.
We can gamble.
Oh my god.
Gambling totally worth it.
Ah!
Oh no.
Bombs.
I love gamble.
Oh, more HP.
Okay, we're gonna save the last two coins.
Something special.
Wait, what is going on in here?
Why can't I enter?
Wait, did I just...
Did I just take damage from my own?
Oh wait, I think I hit the rock down here.
The spike I see now.
I hit the spiky rock.
I thought I took damage from my own circle.
Okay.
Cheers, guys.
Oh yeah, man.
This is a blast!
I'm winning the game.
I could go left or I can go down.
I don't have a lot of money, but I'm gonna get money via gambling.
Don't gamble, kids.
It's a bad idea.
What's that?
Omega?
Libra, you feel balanced.
Oh, it balanced my stats or what?
I don't know if that was good or not for me.
Honestly, it could have been both, you know.
Uh,
wait, did we just get 12 coins?
Uh, bot repellent?
Jar of Flies, bot catcher.
Okay, okay.
Oh, it replaces the gambling.
Wait, how does that work, though?
Gamble 24-7.
Keep gambling.
Okay, that was it.
No more gamble.
Now I'm gonna take this.
Look at me optimizing the shit out of this.
I don't know what this is gonna do for me, but it's probably good.
Uh, I have a bad feeling.
Jesus!
Wow.
They came quite quick there.
Oh.
Oh no.
So many bullets everywhere.
There you are.
Come out, come out.
Jesus.
Let's go this way.
More gambling.
Oh, I wish I could get in there.
I can't... Wait, oh, I didn't even see that guy.
Huh.
I was looking down here trying to figure out if I needed a key for this stone.
It looks like a keystone to me.
Yeah, a keystone.
But it doesn't look like I can use a key.
Boss room?
Wait, why can't I move my... Oh, it's stuck on the...
Wait, that was weird.
I couldn't move this past a certain point over here.
Ah, weird.
Uh, let's not do boss yet.
Go back.
Kill everything.
Just stay at range.
Judgment.
Judge?
Uh, lest he be judged.
Rotten penny has appeared in... Bro, I have no idea what the fuck is going on in this game.
A rotten penny has appeared in the basement, and I now have a million blue circles around me.
Or flies, whatever.
Like, I don't understand what is going on.
And what is with that Super Soaker on the left side?
I couldn't get in there for some reason.
Let me try again.
Let me in.
Maybe I need to blow it open?
No.
Let me in.
Hmm.
There's also a room in the top left.
I don't know what that is.
Let's check that out.
Up here.
Oh, it's this one that... Okay, we can actually go in here.
Fuck it.
Give me hearts.
No hearts?
No.
That was not worth it at all.
Okay.
Let's just go to the boss.
I feel it's time for boss.
Oh, I almost stepped on the thingies.
Uh, wait, can I go through here?
Oh, that's a hole.
How does this, uh, thing... Also, if I press Q right now, I'm gonna...
Wait, judgment.
Judgment.
Huh?
Wait, what?
What?
There's a tiny baby holding a card with the letter C on it, and he just ate my coin?
Yeah, okay.
Sure.
I have no idea what that's all about.
Isaac versus mom!
Oh, no way.
Oh my god.
There's ants everywhere.
Kill all the ants.
She's yelling, Isaac.
Oh, uh, it's when the foot comes down.
Isaac was cornered.
His mother fueled the desire to serve her god was bearing down on Isaac.
God, I love you above all else.
Isaac's mother repeated to herself.
This was the end of the line for Isaac.
His mother was far too strong for him.
But just as he accepted his fate, God intervened, sending an angel down from above to stop his mother's hand.
And just like that, it was over.
Whoa!
What?
That's it?
You're kidding me.
Did I just fucking nail the game in, like, what?
An hour?
Hello?
Let's wait a bit.
Wait, how did people spend a thousand hours on this?
Unless they're talking about, I don't know, maybe doing all achievements or something.
You kidding me?
That was a good game.
I like this.
What should we play next?
I'm sure there's like an act two or something.
You unlocked the womb.
You unlocked challenge.
Okay, okay.
I unlocked speed.
I like speed.
Pride day.
The guardian?
Wait, I don't understand what's happening here.
April's Fool.
Dude, I love this song that's playing right now.
Did it just say, I unlocked item description?
Hahaha.
That's funny.
Wait, what?
I guess I...
I guess I just play hard.
I don't understand, like, did I...
I'm actually so lost right now.
I understand it's a roguelike, of course.
But that is a very short roguelike.
I don't really know what I'm supposed to do next.
I guess we just go for a harder difficulty.
Oh wait, we also have characters.
So none of these are unlocked.
Random.
We can go random, I guess.
Random on hard.
Let's do it.
What's it gonna be?
No way!
We got Isaac again!
Hahaha.
Okay.
Oh, that's so weird.
I'm shooting normally now.
Okay, well, Isaac versus Brad.
Oh, he only has one way to come here.
Oh my god, it's a bummer man!
Bummer man!
I found for you, sir.
Hahaha.
Who is the bummer man now?
It ain't you, buddy.
It's me.
I am the one who bombs.
You hear me?
I shall be bombing.
All right, guys.
Come here.
Oh, I'm gonna nail this.
Hard?
Haha, come on.
Normal was like Omega Easy.
How hard can hard be?
Oh, I can't pick this up.
Because I'm so good, I didn't even lose any HP yet.
We got little flies!
I forgot whether or not these guys shoot for textiles.
Doesn't look like it.
It looks like they're about to explode the way they're blinking.
My card.
The devil.
Revel in the power of darkness.
Whoa.
Dude, look at Isaac.
He means business.
I don't know what that means, but okay.
Why not?
Let's revel in the power of darkness.
We got to play the smart.
One at a time.
Okay, that's good.
That's good.
Wait, we got a little nasty butts in the floor.
I hate floor butts.
Actually, what all those?
I don't know what they are.
Weird, nasty.
Oh, that's an enemy!
For some reason, I thought he was following me.
I guess he was, but you know what I mean.
Okay, they released these little bastards, huh?
Spider?
Mutant spider, quat shot.
Whoa!
I have four eyes!
God damn, he's being, you know, made fun of, and he has glasses.
Doesn't get worse for Isaac.
Oh my god, the damage.
There we go.
Temperance?
What?
I didn't get to read it.
Why is it so fast?
Okay, let's try this.
I knew it.
Okay, yeah, that's exactly what I thought it would be.
Good to know I'm right about that.
Uh, oh, look at this!
Donation is still 18.
Make it 20.
Store upgrade, level one.
Dude, we gotta donate every time.
This is like a way to upgrade the run between runs.
Oh wait, I almost ran into the boss room.
I'm not gonna do that yet.
Uh, wait, there's hearts down here?
Oh, shit.
Sweet.
There's also room in the very bottom we gotta go to.
There's, oh, there's keys here.
I can trade a bomb for a key.
Let's do it.
Sweet.
Uh, interesting.
Oh wait, I need to step on that?
Or no, okay.
I don't know what the point is of this room.
I was in a similar room before, then something appeared.
But now it didn't.
Good news is we can heal again.
Uh, let's go, let's go to the boss.
What's it gonna be?
Gemini.
Okay, so we, oh man, did you see the heart?
The heart shape?
It's kind of cool.
All right, I'm gonna kill the little guy first.
Wait, is my attack, uh, attack speed, like, significantly down?
Because it feels super slow.
Yeah, it is totally.
Oh, that sucks.
It's more like a shotgun now, then.
I'm trying to kill the little guy first.
Oh no.
Okay.
I mean, this is, this is fine, the way I'm doing this here.
This tactic is working!
Don't change what's already working.
Play safe!
I don't think I like this, uh, quad shot thingy.
Is that a bib?
Binky, tears up.
Okay.
I feel like I have faster attack speed right now.
Maybe it's placebo.
Let's go down.
I have a blue heart.
It's like an extra heart.
Isaac is thinking about Isaac, thinking about Isaac, and it's giving him existential dread.
Recursive thinking.
It's no good for anyone.
Okay.
What are these little things, anyway?
Little Star Hoppers.
Okay.
What is this room here?
Let me in!
Oh, wait a minute!
This opens when I kill the boss, I guess.
There's like a skull and two swords.
That's what I'm gonna assume.
So when you kill the boss, you can go back and grab it.
Okay, go in here.
Okay.
Money and a bomb.
Very nice.
Oh, we got a bunch of little yellow ones.
What's the difference between yellow and the other ones?
Shouldn't the spider be my friend?
I'm also a spider now.
I'm an arachnid.
Uh, up here.
Dude, the heart doesn't even feel hard.
Hello?
The butterbean has appeared.
Sure, whatever.
Is the butterbean a real thing?
Like, I don't even know what that means.
Butterbean.
Sounds American.
I'm putting myself in a bad spot here.
Oh, they're farting.
That's not good.
Okay, the shotgun is kind of good.
I like the shotgun.
It's good at AOE.
Crowd control.
Extinguish the fires.
Acquire money.
Oh, god.
I need to watch for the projectiles.
Wow.
I took unnecessary damages now.
Oh, no!
I took even more unnecessary damage.
That's horrible.
Oh, crap.
I released the horde.
Dude,
imagine if you can get an ability that makes your projectiles bounce off walls.
And you have this on, you can go in a small place like this, and then have it bounce back and forth.
You know, that could be cool.
I don't know if that's a thing.
Uh, boss?
Not yet.
We gotta find HP.
There is a shop up here.
But I have no money.
Never mind, I have money.
No, not enough.
What is this little statue here?
Or this little cuddly teddy bear thingy?
I don't think I like the look of that.
So, the middle one is a map.
This one is a pill.
I could go down here.
Scissors?
The pinking shears.
Cut and run.
Wait, what?
I'm so confused.
Huh?
Now I'm back to normal.
Yeah, I don't know what that was about.
What is the point of that?
Interesting.
Okay, let's go to the boss.
Monstro?
Disgusting.
Okay.
Oh!
Oh, okay, I see your stance.
I see your shit.
You gonna jump again?
Not jumping.
You're jumping now.
I got your number.
You ain't nothing.
You ain't nothing?
Nice projectiles you got there.
Oh, okay, they were pretty nice.
I didn't want to get a close-up at it.
Get closer.
You gonna jump?
I think being close is kind of risky.
We got him!
A syringe.
This could be good or bad.
Speedball.
Speed plus shot speed up.
Like a stimpack.
From Starcraft.
We need medivacs, though, for this to work.
Man, he's crying so much.
I feel so bad for Isaac.
This is like a nightmare, actually.
Wait, so there's two keys needed here for a red room.
Whoa, we gotta check it out.
Huh?
What the frick is this?
Oh, oh, oh!
What happened?
Wait, what?
I am now...
I now shoot green stuff.
Did it just randomize some stuff I had?
Maybe that's what happened.
I'm not gonna go in there, because I don't have any HP.
It's very dangerous.
Oh, no, we got these weirdos.
Oh, I shoot poison!
That's huge!
Kill him.
Very nice.
That's what that is.
Whoa!
Man, I wish I could shoot diagonally.
It's not a thing.
Whoa.
Okay, okay, we're good, we're good.
Okay, it's getting a little bit risky here.
Also, I can use something here.
Monster manual.
Huh?
Oh, I don't understand why this happened just now with the monster manual.
So, when I fill this up, he's gonna puke.
Projecta, okay.
They got me in a corner!
Shit!
Okay, okay, okay.
That was crazy.
We go again.
There's no way I'm letting myself get beaten like that.
Come on now.
Okay, there's definitely a lot of variety here.
Every room is different.
What is even happening here?
It's a waste of oil!
Nice.
They're not that bad.
I'll take them out.
I'm just super overwhelmed by everything that's happening.
Like, I don't understand how the things that I'm picking up, you know?
Like, I do something, and then suddenly everything's different, and I don't know why.
Okay, I'm full on HP.
Okay, there's poop in there.
Why would it be in there?
I feel like it's gotta be the good poop.
Let's get it out.
A lucky rock!
Wait, what?
I didn't get to read it!
And fuck you!
Let me read the shit before you disappear!
It was a lucky rock!
There's gotta be a way to change that.
So, I can actually read it.
I don't know what's happening, man.
That was close.
What's that?
This looks like a mushroom pill, from the colors.
Retro...
Retro vision.
Okay, okay.
That is weird.
Ow!
Okay, I thought they were just static.
Okay, okay, I see your stance.
I'm gonna kill this guy.
They're all waiting for me here.
Wait, maybe I can sort of...
Oh, did you see that?
Why am I not hitting him?
Oh, it's temporary, okay.
I wasn't sure whether or not that was a buff or not.
Come here!
Oh, no.
Got him!
No problem.
Ooh, hold on.
If I open here, they're gonna come out.
One at a time.
That's how we do it, baby.
Oh, god!
Yeah, nice, nice, nice, nice.
Next!
This guy's purple for some reason.
Don't get stuck in a corner.
That's the bad thing.
You can't let that happen.
Man, it takes so much brain power for me to...
keep watch and see where all the projectiles are and stuff, you know, and where the enemies are moving and...
Like, look at all this crap on my screen.
Literally, I think this is poop.
This is poop.
These are little pooplets.
And I'm gonna take care of them.
Man, projectiles are so slow.
Bomb for me, and we can go to boss.
I'm not gonna, though.
I will never.
I'm going to the shop because I am...
Actually, I don't have that much money.
I can't buy it.
I can buy a PhD.
That's questionable.
More money?
Dude, I should just do this.
Did I just gain luck?
I gained luck by doing that.
And one of that is a thing that happens every round, you know?
If you donate one money, you get one luck.
Maybe.
Let's go in here now.
The Duke of Flies.
Okay.
He's gonna have a lot of flies.
Sure looks like it.
Oh, wait, that doesn't damage him.
We gotta hit him.
Oh, you have a lot of flies, not a sun.
Here, you like bombs?
That's how you take care of flies.
You bomb them.
This guy's not too bad.
Okay, let's take care of him.
Flies here.
Clean up the ads, you know?
You're the Duke of Nothin', you hear me?
There we go.
Oh, wait, the flies are still here.
What's that?
Booster pack, collect them all.
That's Pokemon.
Two of diamonds.
That's what I said.
Okay.
The Hankman, may you find enlightenment?
Is this what enlightenment is like?
Joker.
Huh?
Hell no!
Nope.
I don't like this.
What's that?
Little horn, big brother is watching.
Wake up, son.
Stay mad.
Hello.
Huh?
Wait, what?
The high priestess mother is watching you.
Okay, you never want to use that, I guess.
Two of clubs.
Item multiplier.
Which item, though?
Maybe I need to have an item for that to multiply.
Or maybe it multiplied a random item I had, I'm not sure.
Just keep moving.
Oh, no.
I have Stockholm Syndrome with my mom.
Plus 100% demon mode right now, apparently.
Are these gonna shoot protect us?
Oh, there's little ones up fast.
I'm so glad they didn't shoot anything at me.
Wait, what the?
I just shot a fireball.
Maybe one of the items I have makes me randomly shoot the fireball.
Oh, man, there's so much stuff in there.
What do I want?
I want the heart.
Wait, I only have two hearts I can have.
Oh, shit.
It's... that is bad.
Oh, I can't go in there.
We're in danger.
Yeah!
Christ almighty.
The fireball!
Wait, what was that?
Something just happened.
Oh, wait, there's spikes on that one!
I saw it in time.
I'm not gonna do it.
I'm not doing it.
Wait, what is this red thing in here?
Oh, is it?
It's the card, I guess.
Let me get the card.
The sun.
May the light heal and enlighten you.
That sounds good.
Hey, we got healed.
Nice.
Oh, I don't have any keys.
This way.
Look at all this poop, though.
Golden poop!
That's got to be good.
Wait, is it going to explode on me or something?
No way!
I'm rich!
We got to find a shop stat.
And spend all this money.
Maybe there's more money.
Disgusting.
Oh, I'm full on HP.
Well, if you can call it that.
For some reason, I only have two.
Okay.
There is a shop to the right.
I want to go there.
Oh, crap.
Oh, wow.
This is very bad.
Almost got caught in the corner.
Whoa!
The guy just got fisted.
You saw that?
Thank you.
There's poop up here.
More poop.
Actually, if I walk towards the shots I'm shooting, it's kind of like having a higher attack speed if you think about it.
It's like Doppler effect.
Okay.
Wait, why is there a question mark?
Wait.
Who's a god gamer?
Wait, I can't pick this up.
Wait, what if I put it in the fire?
I don't...
Why can't I pick that up?
Anyway, destroy the fires.
Money.
That's nice.
And healing.
It's a secret room.
There's probably something about these little dolls on the floor.
It's similar to the shop rooms, right?
There's also a doll on the floor there.
Maybe this used to be a shop room.
But now it's not.
Oh, wow.
The fist got him.
Key!
Oh, I can go back and do things.
If I want, I'm gonna go back.
There's a door over here that needed a key.
And I want it.
Holy mantle, holy shield.
It's like an extra heart, I guess.
But it's probably not just an extra heart.
There's something more to that.
I'm not sure what it is.
Oh, maybe it's gonna protect me from stuff like this.
Let's try it.
Okay, I was right!
Hell yeah!
Nice!
Okay, um...
Whoa, it comes back!
I thought it was a one-time thing!
Yo!
That's nice!
I can't go into the shop...
Oh, that's a lot of TNT.
Why is this one red?
Bigger explosion, perhaps?
We may need to stand somewhere...
Oh my god!
Ah, I got fisted!
I don't know why that is happening.
It's gotta be like the horn I have in my head, right?
That is the thing that is responsible for that.
Give me money.
Dude, I have 15 monies.
We can go back to the shop now.
Okay, let's do it.
Shop is back here.
That one is 15.
Looks like an inhaler.
Let's do it.
Nightlight, scared of the dark.
I wonder what that's gonna do, though.
Other than light things up.
Maybe it has another effect.
The guy was hanged at this time, the little doll.
Or teddy bear.
Excuse me, holy shit!
Oh, I ran right into the thing!
Oh my god.
Oh, you know what?
I should just run in a circle here.
This is the smart thing to do.
You'll see.
Wait, why are these guys so...
Oh, I see.
They shoot projectiles.
And then they have poop on their mind.
What's that?
Pretty fly.
For a white guy.
Nice.
I mean, money is always good.
Thank you.
We could go to the boss.
What is that in the bottom left?
Hold on.
That looks suspicious.
We gotta go back for that.
That looks like a chest to me.
All the way back.
I wish I could sprint somehow.
Can I?
No.
Shift doesn't work.
That's like the ultimate sprint button, you know?
Also, there's a key in here.
I could actually get the key.
I'm gonna do it.
Straight one bomb for a key.
Thanks.
Oh!
Oh, thank god I still have a bomb, imagine.
What?
How do I get in, though?
Okay, I don't know then.
No.
Oh, wait a minute.
This is gonna protect me.
And then it comes back and I'm totally cool.
Yeah, look at this.
The bomb's for me.
I can go anywhere now.
The hermit.
Now, you see what life has to offer?
I didn't quite catch that.
Huh.
I got teleported to the shop room.
Tarot card, question marks.
Oh, I don't have any money.
You know what?
25.
Nothing happens at 25.
It's probably 30 then.
Something happens at 30 now.
I'm also not sure what this light actually does.
Go back down here.
Maybe something happens at this door now.
Open up in the name of Jesus and the holy light.
Come on.
Maybe these two bombs.
Oh, shit!
Whoa.
Someone peed their bed.
Wait, am I making myself pretty?
I don't understand what's happening.
Man, this rug really ties the room together.
I wonder who's living here.
What if I had a sister once?
That also went into the basement.
But they were too scared to continue, so they holed up here.
Made themselves pretty there, slept here, peed their bed, because mom was chasing them.
But now I also am down here, and I found the remains of my sister.
I'm totally just throwing shit out of my ass right now, but you know, it sounds good.
It doesn't smell too good, though, but it sounds good.
Okay, let's go to the boss.
Bro, this extra heart I have, or the cross is actually kind of nuts.
This seems like a really good item.
It's Larry Jr. I thought that was Gemini.
Okay, I guess they look very similar.
Oh, my God.
It's like Snake.
Oh, I don't have a lot of range.
Oh, they don't even care about me.
They just go about their own business here, it seems.
I'm in trouble, maybe.
Open up!
Wait, are they...
Are they actually stopping the...
Yeah, they're pooping!
Ah, I see the problem then.
Oh, wait, one of them is way smaller.
Okay, I'm gonna go for the small...
There's too much poop!
Yeah, one of them is down.
That's huge.
Come here, you.
He also destroys his own poop.
Whoa!
Yeah, so...
Oh, he died right before I...
I was in range.
Caddo Ninetales.
Okay, so this one did...
It's just good, I guess.
Like, this is just good to have.
That's good.
An extra heart.
Wait, wait, where's my Holy Cross thingy?
Why doesn't it pop up again?
Maybe it's one per room, actually.
Also, what the hell is this?
What happened?
I was reading.
I didn't know what just happened.
Collect this item once to identify it.
I feel like this is one of those things where if I take this, I'm gonna get cursed and I get a debuff.
Shovel though, that looks good.
We need to go deeper.
Reusable level skip?
I don't want to do that!
You unlocked a sasle.
Oh!
Backstabber, watch your back.
Oh, I guess I do more damage shooting them in the back then?
What about this thing?
Oh.
I have a feeling I just did something bad.
Destroy these flames.
Oh, they're shooting at me!
What the frick, dude?
That would have killed me!
What about this guy?
Let's load these up.
Yeah, fuck you!
Oh, we got spiders.
Uh, I'm leaving.
Yeah, that's not for me.
Wait, I haven't...
Dude, my HP is fucked!
Why do I keep getting lower HP?
I don't understand.
What happened?
This is not good.
Oh, no.
Recursive thinking again.
Caves one.
Okay, hard is definitely harder than normal, I can confirm.
Wait, there's nothing in here.
Huh?
Uh-oh.
Oh, you got fisted.
Is this light doing anything to them at all?
Oh, wait, they actually do get a debuff when I look at them.
Oh, they move slower!
I was wondering what that was.
I see now.
Cool.
Wait, are we somehow slow again?
No, we're...
Oh, it's because I'm moving over this.
Ah, I see.
Okay, so wait, does this mean if I open this, it's bad?
Because it's like a dark and scary room I get cursed?
Oh, okay, it's like a challenge room or so.
I take the treasure, but I have to fight.
We get a pill out of it.
Actually, we get two pills.
But I forgot what those colors did.
Oh, wait, there's more.
Keep the...
Oh, my god, the light even slows projectiles!
Oh, that's super cool!
Okay, the light is awesome.
Oh, these guys are not affected by the light at all.
They don't give a frick.
Oh, his head is gone.
That is disturbing.
That's a little guy inside of him!
What the hell?
Unidentified pill.
Experimental pill.
Lock up and something else.
Range down.
Oh, no.
Shit.
I really need to try and remember the...
colors on those, I guess.
Okay, up.
But apparently, if I find them once, right, it'll tell me?
Nice!
Not bad.
What the hell is that?
Look at that mouth!
Disgusting mouth.
Oh, that's not...
That's a friend.
That's weird.
Oh, here we go.
Okay, that was an easy room.
Another card.
How do I get to these things, though?
Like, I can't jump, you know?
Or can I?
What?
Oh, I pressed space!
I think this is the level skip.
Whoops.
I was just, like, jumping space.
Okay.
I have one coin.
That's not good enough.
What is that?
What kind of... boom.
This is a pill.
Unidentified pill.
Wait, collect this item once.
I know what this is.
It's a bomb.
Come on, now.
Donate money.
Okay, I didn't get luck there.
Maybe the luck thingy is random.
I'm not going to skip a level.
That means I'm going to, you know, skip upgrades.
That sounds like a bad idea for me.
Wait, why can't I hit these guys?
Okay, I can hit them.
Shine that light on them!
There we go.
Got a key now.
Whoa!
Holy crap, dude.
Wait, I can shoot their projectiles, though.
That's nice.
Okay, it's not too bad.
Wait, why is he bleeding?
It's like a bleed icon on him.
Come on.
Finally, he died.
Yeah, there we go.
Um, boss is here.
I'm not going to go in there yet, though.
I'm going to go this way.
Oh, no, what is that?
Oh, it's a gravitational potential!
No thanks.
We got a big old dude and a couple young dudes.
Oh, okay.
So when they die, they release that bullshit.
Got it.
Okay, okay.
The mask.
Infamy.
Blocks damage for sometimes.
Well, that's good, I guess.
Wait, is this supposed to be like Jason, you know, the serial killer?
Nah, get out of there.
Uh, there's still a couple rooms in the bottom.
We got to go there.
Dude, this is...
You know what's cool about this?
This is completely different than the other run I had.
You know, like, it's completely different.
Guppy's color.
Oh, wait.
The fucking fires are shooting me!
No, we don't like that here.
Stop it.
50% chance to be revived with half a heart when taking lethal damage.
That's good, though.
But wait, why does it say zero out of three?
Guppy is my cat, no?
Hey, eternal life.
Very cool.
I would expect to have nine lives, though.
Wouldn't that be more fitting with a cat?
Shit.
This guy needs to die!
Okay, this is gonna...
Oh, man, the way the projectiles get slowed is actually so cool.
Who's gonna pop up first?
You.
That means I go for you.
Wow.
Bye-bye.
Okay.
Hey, key and a bomb!
Not bad.
I don't need any of this, actually, so I can just go to the right now.
I can actually kind of sort of aim it.
You see that?
Shoot around corners.
Like that one movie.
This is not that good, though.
There we go.
Your projectiles are nothing.
Oh, I stepped on the thing, but I got protected.
Because I have the thing.
Lots of things, apparently.
Um, how am I gonna...
I need to sort of angle this, like this.
I can't hit this guy.
It's impossible.
Uh, we may need to bomb him.
There we go.
That's how we do it.
Wake up.
Wait, he's bleeding, it seems.
He had a status effect on him.
Okay, now what?
Uh, we go up again.
So this room right here, there's pee down here.
Why is that?
Pee on the floor.
I want to find more secret rooms, dude!
What was this?
Right.
Okay.
I want to find secrets.
There's a shop up here, and I have no money, so I'm not gonna go there.
For some reason, I thought I was, like, super rich, but I'm not.
Mega fatty!
Oh my god.
He's gonna jump?
Okay, okay.
Got it, got it.
And he poops!
Disgusting.
Wow, he jumped fast!
What the fuck was that?
Why did he jump that fast?
The first jump he did was, like, super slow, and then was, like, meow, the second time.
Is this text the same every time?
I leave all that I own to my cat Guppy.
Oh my god, Guppy.
Who's gonna take care of Guppy now that I'm in the basement?
I don't trust my mom to do that.
No.
Okay.
Basement one.
Okay, here we go!
Dude, I'm...
It's just straight back into it here.
I like it.
What is that?
Spelunker hat.
See-through doors.
Cool.
I like it.
But how does that work?
A see-through doors.
We need to...
I don't see shit.
What do you mean?
Oh, is it the question mark on the map that's been revealed?
Maybe that's what that is, actually.
It allows me to send secrets.
Secret rooms.
That's what I'm gonna get.
Yeah, look, there's something in here.
Should we try?
Dude!
Oh!
It's a chest there, too!
Oh, get rid of the red fire.
Red fire is bad.
Wait, what's happening here?
So, one of these dolls has a wide open mouth.
The two in the center has an O-mouth, and the one in the bottom is, you know, having a seizure.
Does that mean anything?
What if you blow them all up?
I bet you something happens if we blow all of them up.
Ah, I can't open that chest, though.
That's too bad.
Okay, watch this.
I'm gonna step on this, and something's gonna happen.
But I'm not gonna go here yet.
Because what if I find that cross again, you know?
I'm gonna play super smart here.
Get these guys out of the way.
We don't like poop.
Not in this house or basement.
Man, this guy's actually dodging all my shit.
Such agile poop!
I've never seen anything like it.
Okay, further down.
He's gonna shoot?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, he may- Oh, he shoot fast!
He's a fast shooter.
Money plays?
I don't have enough money for that, so let's not do it.
By the way, I don't understand this helmet.
Like, see-through doors?
It doesn't make any sense.
I haven't been able to see through any doors.
Oh wait, actually, I- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
There's a room right below me right now.
Thank you.
Wait, why did I just take damage?
Oh, those are enemies!
I thought they were friendly.
They're shitflies.
The flies that circle the shit, you know?
They exist in real life too.
How come they're not dying?
Oh, oh, oh, I see.
Ah, the poop needs to die first.
Okay, the poop gives them power.
That's kind of a cool mechanic, I like that.
I came from here.
Watch this.
Dude, that is so freaking cool that I can just do- I wonder though, if I didn't have this helmet on, and I just randomly put that bomb there, if this room still would have existed, you know?
Or this room got spawned, because I have the helmet.
I don't know that.
So this little bastard right here, is he gonna steal my money?
See for coin?
I'm gonna give him all my money.
Nothing happened.
Maybe you need to give him five coins.
I'm not sure.
There's gotta be like a threshold.
Something's gotta happen, right?
When you give him enough.
Dude, I hear growling!
There's growling in here.
That is a growling boss.
I have no money anyways, so let's not go to the shop.
Let's just do it.
It's Monstro.
That's fine.
I'm a Monstro specialist.
Okay, that's no- That's no- Oh, okay, okay, okay.
So we always- Okay, I see.
So protectiles right after the jump.
All right, all right, all right!
Calm down, calm down now.
I know you're angry.
Holy shit!
Boy!
Geez.
He's gonna jump now?
Yeah.
Wow, that was a crazy dodge on my part there.
I'm really proud of that.
Oh, get juked!
See that?
It seems to be a little random whenever- or when I can destroy projectiles or not with my projectiles.
Sometimes I can, sometimes I can't.
I'm not sure what the distinguishing- or the distinction is.
What is that?
Blood clot.
Damage and range up.
That sounds really good.
That sounds like only good things.
Hell yeah.
Hmm.
There's a question mark in this room down here.
Why is that?
I mean, other than the fact that it was a question mark room.
Is there more to it that I missed?
Okay.
Well, we're poor.
Can't use any money, so...
Off we go.
Dude, I'm having a blast with this.
This is really fun.
I think it's- No, toilet paper!
That's the worst!
Then you have to crap walk, you know, over to the kitchen table to grab some kitchen paper or kitchen towel.
Then you crap walk back to the toilet.
We've all been there.
Oh, shit!
Come here.
No, I got it twice!
Okay, I- No more mistakes.
Precision gaming.
How am I supposed to do this?
These guys are nuts.
Eh.
Alright, that works.
Kinda.
Should I just run for it?
Oh, my goodness.
This room is absolutely bonkers.
Got him!
Okay, uh, wait, do we need to kill them to move on?
Oh, no, I think we do!
It's actually impossible.
Wait, do we need to kill them?
Hold on.
We do, we have to kill them.
Uh,
why can't I shoot diagonally?
No!
He's down, he's down.
Dude,
this room just went from zero to a hundred.
Wow, I- it's- Oh, I see how I do it now.
Of course.
Oh, that's much better.
Oh, my god, I figured it out.
But it's still difficult.
Wow!
Okay, look at me go, man.
Drive by.
Nice!
Not bad, eh?
Alright, so where do we go now?
If I came from the right side, we can go up.
I'ma do it.
Thank you.
There's a bomb in there.
I mean, I could bomb it, I guess.
But I don't have a bomb, so I could not bomb it, I guess.
I guess wrong.
Oh, this guy jumps over rocks.
There's this big spider down there.
Oh, no!
Okay, he's down.
Hey, I'm here.
Come here.
Oh, my god.
Whew!
One hit and I'm dead.
Goddamn done!
I'm in the trenches here!
Holy shit!
Right, I came from here.
Let's go to the right.
I'm in big danger.
Oh, I'm dead here.
Get this fire out of the way!
Oh, god.
This guy's gonna shoot at me.
So far, so good.
Come on.
Yes.
I nailed that.
I actually...
I'm actually kind of a god gamer.
That was crazy.
I don't believe it myself, but there it is.
Swim trunks?
Camo on these.
Camo kit, huh?
Maybe I'm gonna be invisible to the enemies, or they're gonna have a smaller detection range.
Very weird, though.
I mean, honestly, pink is a fantastic camo.
When's the last time you saw a pink soldier in the wild, you know?
Exactly.
They're that invisible.
What just happened?
Oh.
Oh, I see how this works.
When I enter a room, I become camouflaged.
And while in that state, I'm like an assassin.
I can deal a lot of damage by attacking.
You saw the stats, right?
That's what's happening.
Best friends forever?
Oh my god.
I want that.
Wait, what was that on the wall?
What just happened?
I actually don't know what just happened.
Fuck.
I didn't quite pay attention.
Oh well.
Whatever.
We're gonna head through this door now.
No, we're gonna go back.
There's a hidden room!
Hold up now!
There's no way.
Shovel!
Need to go deeper.
Oh, it's that one, right.
Wait, could I not totally abuse this camo?
In and out of a room.
Just kill one, get out, get back in.
Kill one, get out, back in.
That seems like a crazy strategy.
Seems like a good strategy.
That's a crown.
Wait, when I pick this up, there's gonna be enemies.
And it's gonna be a bad time.
I'm gonna...
Wait a minute, I'm invisible though.
Ah, but the door's probably gonna close, right?
Because it's like an arena.
Let's go look for some health first.
This is probably the smartest thing to do.
Yeah, you don't know I'm here.
I'm invisible.
Wow, did you see that?
Massive damage.
Not bad at all.
Has there ever been HP in this?
Shit.
Maybe.
Oh, you can't see me.
Wait, you can sense me maybe.
Your daddy's on fire.
Good old Lemmy reference.
Wait, what is that?
Oh, it's my items on the right.
I thought there were little panties on the side of the wall there.
Thought I could pick up, you know?
Ah, you can't see me.
How do I do this?
Most effectively.
I'm gonna wait for this little guy to pop up somewhere and then kill him.
Needs to be in a good spot though.
That's a bad spot.
There we go.
Bye-bye!
How cool is that, eh?
Wait, he somehow buffed these guys, I think.
As long as he was alive, these guys had like a little effect on him.
Okay, close one.
Bomb's just randomly appearing, huh?
I don't enjoy that.
Okay, so these guys are buffing the small ones.
He's down.
Jesus.
Okay, is this green stuff still toxic?
No, it's fine, okay.
Wow, dude, it's over.
I don't have any HP.
No, there's no HP anywhere.
This is gonna be a tough one.
It's Dingle though.
Can it really be tough?
I feel like Dingle is super duper easy.
Wow, he still sees me.
No, I can't believe it.
I can't believe that happened.
No, it was such a good run.
No, oh my gosh.
Okay, okay, we gotta go again.
Before we do though, I'm gonna take a break.
This game is actually kind of funny.
I like it.
Guys, I'll see you in five minutes.
Have a good one.
What's up?
Jackie jumped up on the table and is sitting right in front of the microphone.
I think it's her time to stream now.
She's like, let me, let me play.
Let me show you how it's done.
No, Jackie, you can't.
The binding of icing is not for cats.
Even though you would really love it.
What's up, guys?
Are you having a blast?
Because I am.
I do love myself a roguelike and this is a good one so far.
Can we get music a bit lower?
Uh, hold on.
Let me escape to the main menu.
We
can take it one notch down.
Is the music too loud overall?
Do we all agree on that or?
I just want to make sure it's not just one guy, you know?
Good.
Infinite regression.
Hey, Quantic.
Yes.
Watching this blind feels like a fever dream.
Oh, you mean like you haven't played either.
Or did you mean like it's a fever dream to watch me play because I'm playing it blind.
Because I can see how that makes sense, in that case.
I think I'm doing okay, you know?
Oliver, you pressed shift, which toggles descriptions on and off.
So watch out for not turning them off, actually.
Oh, okay.
I thought they got turned on because I unlocked them.
I unlocked descriptions, though.
Didn't I unlock them?
It was a bit loud.
Okay, so now it's one notch lower.
Maybe it's better now.
What about the SFX, the sound effects?
Is it a good level?
Did you ever play Y8 when you were younger?
I don't know what Y8 is.
Y8?
No, I don't know about that game.
You can read pop-ups in the menu.
Okay, thank you.
That's actually... stuff like that is fine.
I like that information.
How do I do that?
Let me see.
Stats, maybe?
Oh, my... oh, this is actually kind of cool.
East area.
Drowning gaper.
And a gaper.
Oh, wharf.
Cloddy.
Mulligan.
Claws.
Hooter.
Gusher and pacer.
Okay, these are cool names.
I bet there's a lot of enemies.
Oh, my god.
Wait, how is this possible?
Oh.
How are there this many enemies?
It just... what?
Okay, I'm definitely...
I've definitely not even reached act two or something yet, then.
Mom.
Hits one, death zero, encounters four.
What?
How does that make sense?
Encounters one.
Maybe it's just the heal.
Oh,
and it just keeps going, look at this.
Holy shit.
Wait, why is there only four per page?
Um...
Okay.
Items.
Holy fuck me.
Jesus Christ.
All right, all right, all right.
Endings.
Okay, that's crazy.
Okay, hold on, that's crazy now.
We're going back in.
Oh, yeah, we also unlocked something new, didn't we?
This guy, a sasle.
But hold on a minute.
I haven't even beaten hard.
I need to beat hard.
Oh, that sounded wrong.
Wind streak minus two?
What do you mean?
That's not right.
I'm going in.
Oh, I love that when you transition.
That's nice.
Dude, let's go.
I'm having a blast, man.
This time, I'm going to own.
This is the run.
I'm going to play flawless.
Now I'm going to play flawless.
It didn't count.
The spider right here.
His head is upside down for some reason.
Are spiders upside down in real life?
Think about it.
I think they may be.
Okay, so these guys can traverse past rocks.
That was close.
Okay, nice.
That was a sick shot, actually.
Kind of proud of that one.
He's for me.
Yo, I have three bombs.
I can exchange it for money.
Okay, check this out.
I'm going to do something crazy here, okay?
I'm going to put a bomb here.
And it will destroy the rock.
But if there's a secret room, it will also open a door.
Let's test.
Okay, never mind.
Maybe there is a secret room.
Maybe not.
Maybe you need the item to spawn the secret room.
But I hope that's not the case.
Otherwise, I don't know.
It feels kind of bad, right?
Oh my goodness!
I just took like a shit ton of damage.
This room is evil!
Oh!
Yeah, this room was definitely evil.
Is this the key?
Feels like a trap.
That's a dreamcatcher.
And we can also get a bag of goodies.
Donate.
I'm going to get to 30 on that.
Oh, you know what I think is going to happen here, guys?
The more I donate, the more these shelves are going to be filled in this room.
Notice how there's more stuff on the shelves now.
At least I think there is.
That's what's going to happen.
Maybe we're going to get like 10 items to choose from at some point.
I'm stuck in a corner!
Wow!
Oh!
Killed it!
Oh no, I'm almost dead already!
Dude, I'm getting crazy rooms in this run.
It's totally not me, it's the game.
I'm playing flawless, you know?
It's the game that's fucking me.
I'm kidding, of course.
It's all me.
There's no cope here.
Give me that.
I think that's...
Man, it slid all the way across, huh?
So listen to the...
RARRRR!
On the other side of that wall.
I think it's Monstro.
I think you can maybe hear what monster it is.
And in this case, it's Monstro.
Watch me be right.
Do I want these coins?
Nah.
I'm going to go to these rooms first.
Kill the little guys.
Are these guys going to shoot?
Nope, they're just fast.
Oh, they also charge.
Okay, not too bad.
Uh, that room is kind of questionable.
Blow this up.
I kind of wish these were near the center of the wall, so I can actually maybe find a secret.
Do I go in there?
Nah, wait, let's go to the other room first.
What's that?
Glaucoma.
Blind tears.
That's like a disease, right?
Glaucoma.
Blind tears.
I don't understand.
What does it do?
I don't know what it does.
Oh, I'm going to blow...
Oh, there's a...
Ah, hold on.
Blow it up.
Oh.
Spiders.
I thought buttons were good.
Can I hit this thing from here?
Oh, I can.
Didn't do anything.
So, should I walk on this?
It was not worth it.
Oh, no.
It's going to be a short one, boys.
There's no way I can make it.
You know what?
I'm going to go donate my money if I'm going to die anyway.
We can get to 30.
Nothing at 30, huh?
That's too bad.
Wish me luck!
It's got to be Monstro.
Oh, shit.
Okay, never mind.
Gemini.
This one is kind of tough.
I think this one is hard.
So fast!
Wow.
Wait, he's...
He's...
Oh, he got blinded by my glaucoma, I think.
That's what that does.
Oh, yeah.
You like that?
Wow, that was close.
Oh, my God.
Why is the little guy not dying?
I hit him like a million times.
Okay, there we go.
He wouldn't stop chasing me.
Oh, you're blinded now, aren't you?
You're mine.
I can't hit anything.
I guess I'm also kind of blind.
Oh, God.
Wait, he's exhausted.
There we go.
What's that?
Gemini, conjoined friend.
I am the Gemini.
I am a Gemini now.
I don't know what it's good for, though.
We're playing with our little stick, and Mom is angry and broken.
That is just so fucking cruel.
I swear to God, I'm going to murder Mom.
What's the point of this little guy?
We have three keys.
We can do this.
Oh, my God.
Holy shit.
We need a shop now.
Uh-oh.
Oh, nice!
It's like a little rabbit dog on a leash.
I like it.
Thirteen is the amount of money I currently have.
Oh, man, this is so good.
The Gemini is amazing.
Is Gemini like some kind of Greek goddess or something?
It's some kind of mythological creature, no?
Maybe something that has...
I don't know, maybe a conjoined queen.
Or something.
What's up, dude?
Nothing.
There we go.
No problem at all.
Next, we got Poop Man.
I'm not afraid of Poop Man.
Okay, he jumps at me.
That is actually kind of scary.
Thanks, buddy.
This is my best buddy now.
Uh-oh, uh-oh.
I'm kind of in a pickle here.
How come you say in a pickle?
You know, what do pickles have to do with trouble?
That's a weird saying, isn't it?
What's going here?
Uh, I've seen this before.
This is...
Companion?
Sworn Protector.
Yeah!
Wait, why is it not here?
Where's my Sworn Protector?
We need to summon it?
No?
Maybe it's because I already have a companion.
It doesn't work.
That's weird.
You.
Oh, God.
Hey, thank you, buddy.
Thank you.
I appreciate it.
Man, there's almost nothing in these poops here.
Wait, where's the boss?
Is this in here?
Dude, the Gemini does so much damage.
I have no bombs.
Oh, no.
Get him, Gemini!
Oh, my God, it goes through walls!
Okay, that's sick.
This is actually amazing.
Look at that.
Right?
That is incredible.
Nice.
There's more.
There we go.
He's gonna protect me from the little guys while I take care of these guys.
It's so good.
No bombs, though.
There's the boss.
Apparently, there's a bomb in here.
Oh.
Oh, I can't afford it.
I want the boom.
Should I donate everything?
Do it!
Everything goes in.
Or maybe until 40.
Plus one luck!
We're gonna donate everything we ever owned.
Time for the boss.
Larry Jr. Okay.
All right, this is that guy.
I just need to stay close so my little buddy can do some damage.
Oh, he's blinded.
Dude, that's huge.
So good.
Wow.
A milk carton.
Breakfast.
HP up.
Oh, dude.
Okay, this is actually a run.
We got a run on our hands here.
What's this?
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
This is... I understand what's happening now.
If I pick this up, I lose a heart.
But I don't know what it is.
I think I should do it just to see what it is.
How come I can't see the...
Oh, wait.
Oh, oh, okay.
I actually haven't clicked shift.
Collect this item once to identify it.
I'm gonna do it.
Circ...
Ocular Rift.
I got minus on the cross there.
I don't know what that stat is.
And I got plus on the demon mode.
Okay.
Maybe the demon mode is like a difficulty modifier.
Not sure.
Yeah, I'm not sure about that at all.
I don't think that was worth it.
Man, wait, did we actually get buried alive in a treasure chest by mamas or something?
Or we couldn't breathe, because that's kind of horrifying.
Rap!
I've got my little buddy with me, though.
And he angry, he angry.
Oh, yeah.
Come here.
Right, that's you.
You do that.
Wait, is that your boss?
Nice!
Not bad at all.
Get him, get him!
Yeah, good boy, good boy.
That was also like a little gravitational potential there that sucked the coin in.
I'm not sure how that happened.
Oh, now we have the little protector around us.
We didn't have that before.
Not sure what I did.
That's different here.
Okay, just keep moving.
Most important part.
Wait, is that two hearts?
That's kind of massive.
Nice!
I feel like I need more damage.
I'm not dealing that much damage.
I need damage up.
Come on, Isaac.
What was that?
Jesus.
I mean, he has a tell.
Okay, so that happened again just now.
I think that's what happens with my item that I have.
Can I somehow see my...
Can I see a description of the item right now?
My stuff?
Oh!
Oh, that's massive.
Chance to fire tears that summon a rift where they land.
That makes sense.
The rifts last for two seconds, pulling pickups and enemies toward them and dealing rapid contact damage to enemies, right?
Okay, chance increases with luck.
Cool!
Beelzebub, one of three.
Fun taking damage spawns a fly familiar for the current room that orbits Isaac and deals contact damage.
I see.
And Gemini, familiar that is bound to Isaac and will attack nearby enemies.
That's simple enough.
And Glaucoma, chance to fire concussive tears that confuse enemies struck.
Confusion applied by this item lasts much longer than most status effects.
Ha!
Yeah, it's a very long duration.
Very cool.
Sick.
So, what does that mean?
I can just...
Yeah, look at that.
So, I can actually shoot black holes just to get items.
Massive.
That's gonna change everything.
Look at this.
You ready?
Come on now.
Any day now.
Oh, wait, no.
Okay, wait, wait.
Oh, they don't go flying over the edge.
I thought I was being so smart.
Turns out I wasn't.
Whoa, what's up with all these black holes something like?
What are the chances of that happening?
Wow.
Get sucked in.
Kill the apple.
Or tomato, whatever that is.
It keeps growing if you don't damage it.
Wake up.
I'm playing so meticulous right now.
And go.
He's confused.
There we go.
Child's heart!
10% increased chance of finding red hearts as room clear rewards.
33% chance to add an additional red heart to chests, tinted rocks, and destroyed machines.
Okay, so, wait, room clear rewards.
There's always like a reward for clearing a room.
Or maybe there's not always, but this definitely was a room reward.
Because we got the chest, no?
It calls out to its brothers.
Okay, so wait, that item is in the bottom left now.
That's a different type of item.
Hold on.
So maybe we can only have two of those items in the bottom?
One on each side?
Or wait, no.
Yeah, I think so.
Or maybe just one.
Maybe you can only have one of those?
How do I know which one is which, though?
Like, how do I know which item is the one that goes in the bottom left?
Or the one that goes on the right side of the screen?
Experience, maybe?
Yeah, I got sucked in by the black hole!
That was crazy!
Oh my goodness, you can't tell me that was nuts.
I need more black holes here.
We gotta suck that thing in.
Come on now.
Yeah.
Oh no, no, you put it in the wrong spot.
I think it can go this way and then successfully come out.
You'll see.
No, it's stuck.
Gimme, gimme the pill!
Damn.
I mean, I could blow it up, I guess.
Yeah, let's do it.
Yeah.
It's a golden pill, it's gotta be good.
Speed up!
Okay, so golden is speed up.
Got it.
Ah, but wait, is this a...
short-term modifier?
I need to pay attention to that.
I think there's a higher chance of spawning these black holes when I hit enemies with it.
Friendship necklace.
Familiars orbit around Isaac.
Oh!
Oh, wait, okay, so...
So this Gemini is actually considered a familiar, and right now he's not orbiting.
But if I put this on, he is.
To me, though, that doesn't make too much sense, because this guy is already sort of homing towards enemies.
So this is better.
At least right now.
If I had more flies, that would have been better, I think, in that case.
Is that a master key?
A key that will open all doors?
No, no more money.
I'm gonna donate.
We got luck?
Okay.
Keep moving.
This is a great run, man.
This is fantastic.
And it looks like the speed up effect is permanent.
Either that or it's very long duration.
Did I just get hit?
Wait, is my familiar absorbing projectiles?
Bombs.
Okay.
Yo, should we try something crazy?
See?
Right here.
I can smell it.
Nevermind.
We're moving on.
You didn't see that.
Let's go to this room instead.
There's definitely stuff waiting for me here.
I have no keys.
I thought I had like five.
What happened to my five keys?
What a scam.
They're just gone.
All black hole.
You know what we call this in the Starcraft world?
An Archon toilet.
The Gemini right now is my Archon.
And I'm the mothership.
I didn't mean to answer!
Pin?
Double trouble.
No!
Oh, we got chin.
Oh my goodness.
He jumps fast.
We gotta be careful.
That's a lot of fuel.
Get sucked in by the thingy.
Oh, you're gonna die now.
He's sucking me in.
Why are you taking so little damage?
Okay, well, there we go.
Plot plot.
Plus one d- What's happening?
What was that?
Plus one damage and plus two seven five range for i6 left eye.
Huh?
So it's every second shot.
Oh my god.
His tears.
What is that sound I'm hearing?
What?
Oh, I got a piece of white heart.
I'm not sure what that means.
I hope it's good.
Ah, we're not gonna enter yet.
I'm gonna go back.
That's right.
I have room to explore.
Oh, get stunned!
Or confused, technically.
Nice.
Kill him!
Come on!
Oh, Gemini.
I
like this little robot operator.
Oh, oh!
Okay, so it's like an extra heart on a heart.
It's like a little shield that I had, I guess.
That's cool.
And now it's gone.
I'm gonna go- Oh!
Oh, we got a crazy pill.
It's gotta be crazy, right?
For this?
To be an arena?
Good job, Gemini!
You are the man!
It's you and me against the world, buddy!
Oh god.
Oh, this is gonna be tough.
Oh!
Oh my god!
Oh man, this was so difficult.
There's more?
Dude!
Watch this music!
Okay, we got a key.
That's huge.
But what did we actually pick up here?
I forgot what we picked up here.
Oh yeah, a pill!
Right?
No!
Wait, how do I know?
Are there really that many pills?
I feel like I picked up so many, I should be able to identify them now.
What's this?
Okay, come on.
What's happening in here?
There's a skull on this one.
There's water flowing down here.
Does that mean anything?
I'm gonna blow it up!
No!
It was a waste.
It didn't mean anything.
You know what?
I could actually go up there because there's hearts to be picked up somewhere else in the vicinity.
But it's risky.
I think I'm gonna pick up this heart first.
Oh wait, there's two hearts!
That's two hearts, isn't it?
So I'm actually not gonna do that.
I'm gonna go in here now.
Yeah.
Oh god!
Wow!
No!
Bro!
Oh, I should have used the bomb to open this chest.
I learned my lesson.
Let's go pick up these two hearts.
These two hearts, right?
Yeah!
Okay, nice!
Totally back on top now.
I'm gonna go to that golden room.
Why have I not been in there yet?
Oh, I didn't have a key.
I see, I see.
Ooh, what's that?
Hyromaniac!
It hurts so good!
Plus five bombs.
Oh, look at my face!
Wait, what's happening here?
I need to see this.
Plus five bombs, immunity to explosions and fires?
Getting hit with an explosion heals?
Oh my god, that is so good!
Hello!
Oh, let's go, baby!
That is massive!
Yeah!
Uh, oh, I don't have any money, though.
Wait, what am I supposed to do now?
Oh, we killed the boss already!
True.
We go back.
We go to the next stage.
This is the run, guys.
This is actually it.
I feel like I'm on top of the world right now.
Nothing can go wrong.
Level four.
We got the tit squirt!
That brings good luck, I think.
Every time I had that, I won.
Sup, bro?
Isaac versus I didn't catch your name.
Sorry.
Okay, you're going to do something like that.
That's cool.
I like it.
I respect it.
Dude, am I killing it or what?
Oh, nah!
Why did I say that?
Come on, Gemini.
Do your thing.
Okay, that works.
Let's go down here.
Heh heh heh.
Look at this train of fools.
One of them has a golden eye.
Wait, why are they all...
Oh, they need to die at the same time?
Hey, okay, so we have an extra heart now.
That's huge.
What the hell is that?
He's confused.
Nice.
Blow open the TNT.
Hell yeah.
Caves two...
Wait, why is it caves two?
Shouldn't it be four?
Come here, you.
I really should play more safe.
I'm sort of, like, reckless.
Not a good idea.
Ah!
Obviously, I'd do that.
We got a familiar.
I'm kind of saving my bombs because they are healing, right?
Worst case scenario, I can always heal a little bit.
Which is a great feeling.
This guy is mega on fire.
What's pulling the chest?
Okay, wait a minute.
How do I get to that chest?
Let's think about this.
I can't jump.
I don't know.
I need to get some kind of ability that allows me to jump.
That's what I need to do.
Oh, god.
Wait, I actually have an insane idea.
You ready for this?
Okay, I'm gonna explain what my idea was.
I was gonna place the bomb, have the explosion, push the chest out of the way.
But it was out of range!
I'm gonna try again, one more time.
Ah!
It's over!
Yeah!
Oh, no!
Wait, I'm an idiot.
I have black hole.
Black hole!
I'm so dumb!
Oh, what the hell.
I actually cannot believe that.
It was a good idea, though.
I think it was a good idea.
That is a garlic snipper.
The scooper plop, huh?
Scoops out I6 right eye, turning it into a peeper familiar for the current room.
While active, tears from the right eye socket deal 50% more damage.
Wait a minute, which eye is my...
Oh, no, my good eye is my left eye, though.
No, okay, wait, that's a black hole.
Okay, I'm not sure, actually, what's happening here.
Okay, so it's only for the room.
Got it.
And why is it good?
Oh, it's just a familiar that will help me, I guess.
Okay, sure.
We got flies.
When there's poop, there's flies.
Okay, so watch this.
This door's gonna open when I kill a boss, 100%.
We're gonna come back here after the boss.
Oh, no, I just assumed he would die before he reached me.
That was a bad assumption.
Hey, nice.
I got no keys.
That's not good.
Dude, you know what that little item looks like on the very right?
It looks like a wand from Noiter.
In the room that I can't access.
I want it bad.
I'm gonna wake up.
Come on, wake up.
Nice.
Wait, call me crazy.
Have I been in this exact room before?
Like, this layout is familiar to me.
Oh, this one is tough.
How do I even...
Wait, he didn't do any damage to me.
There we go.
Is my familiar actually absorbing damage?
No, I don't think so.
Oh, dude, I can push him!
Get over there!
Yo, what the hell?
That's kind of massive.
I can push the enemies around.
That guy's blue.
Blue, da, ba, dee, da, da.
You took...
Oh, I don't know why he's blue.
Why is he blue?
He's confused, though.
Okay, when he's confused, he can't shoot.
That was smooth as hell.
Heck yeah.
Let me try this now.
I got an eye familiar.
Jesus Christ.
Oh, wait, they're bombs!
Right.
I have to remember that.
Unidentified pill?
Explosive...
Oh, but that heals me!
Hey!
Yeah!
Diarrhea's never felt so good.
Now, this is a keystone.
Wait, what?
Did I actually just put a key in there?
I don't know if I had a key.
I didn't pay attention.
I think it may have been a key that I used there.
Ah, okay, fine.
Wait, is it still gonna hurt me?
We're gonna black hole it.
Suck the coins into me!
Yeah, look at that.
Is that amazing or what?
Okay, I'm not gonna go in there yet.
Yes, I am.
Fuck it, let's go!
Boom, baby!
Fistula!
I shall punish you!
You ain't got nothing on me!
You may be able to fist, but I can...
I can...
Shoe.
That's right, I put my shoe inside of you.
You hear me do?
Oh no, I'm actually kind of dying.
Who am I kidding?
I'm not.
I'm actually kind of winning.
I'm a winner.
Kill him!
Yeah!
Thank you.
Roid rage.
Speed and range up.
That sounds really good.
Dude, look at that range.
Crazy.
Let's go back.
I think we can access that one room now.
I'm not gonna be wrong, because I'm right.
What's this room?
Maybe I should have picked up some health first.
Hey, give me that.
I do have five bombs I can use to heal.
It sounds crazy when you're always throwing bones at me.
These guys are new.
It's a new enemy.
Not bad at all.
Yeah, do it.
Fuck it.
Oh, not these flames.
I wonder if there's any indication when they're gonna shoot.
Death, lay waste to all that oppose you.
Okay, wait, wait, I'm not gonna use this.
Two of spades, item multiplier.
Oh, fuck, I keep thinking I need to hit space to...
I was thinking space, space, fucking...
There we go.
Did I multiply anything?
I'm not sure how that works.
So it's Q I press to do this.
I'm not gonna do it yet.
I think when I click this, everything in the room dies except me.
So I'm not gonna click it yet.
This is how I think this works.
In fact, let me just read it.
Just confirm...
Oh, wait, can I?
Oh, yeah, okay.
So it deals 40 damage to enemies in the room.
It's not a kill, though.
It's 40 damage.
So it depends how much HP they have.
That's good to know.
Oh, what the...
Oh, oh.
Hey, I don't know how to get to that.
That seems pretty much impossible.
I think these guys need to die at the same time.
Otherwise, they come back alive.
Yeah, look at that.
Look at that.
They need to die at the same time.
Die!
We got him.
Bombs would have been good here, actually.
Hey, nice.
A coin for my efforts.
So that green bar in the top left, I think that replenishes when I deal damage.
That's my guess on that.
I could be wrong.
I'll have to pay attention to it.
But now let's try and go to this room over here and see if it works.
Oh, no.
Wait, so how the hell do I get in there?
Oh, I can buy this ring.
Ah, no!
You asshole!
I didn't even see that.
Wow.
I'm gonna buy it.
Mom's bracelet.
Mother's strength.
Where is it?
Yes, mother.
Grab and pick up a rock or other stationary obstacle.
Press an attack button to throw a health object.
Smashing it and dealing damage to enemies struck.
Whoa.
So wait, I...
Oh, wait, this is a...
Oh, it's a use item.
Okay, I'm starting to understand what's happening.
So there's actually three types of items.
There's passive items, which are those on the right side of the screen.
They're just always there doing their thing, right?
Then we have an item that can be used with space, and that's the one I have in the top left.
Then we have an item that can be used with Q, which is the one in the bottom right.
But then we also have an item in the bottom left, which is, I guess, also a passive item.
So why is it not in the right side?
That I don't know.
Maybe it's because it's more, I don't know, crazy than the others.
And the reason why I just left that item on the floor is because I can only have one usable item in the top left.
Notice, by the way, that there's a little battery icon with three next to it.
I think I know why I couldn't pick up the battery.
It's because I didn't have a battery meter or my battery was full.
So that's what that battery does.
It's starting to make sense.
I need to heal myself, though.
So check this out.
I'm gonna do some crazy experiments here.
Wait, it's open!
Okay, this door opens when all rooms have been cleared.
That's what that means.
It's a chicken.
Squeezy.
Cheers.
Up.
I don't like this right now.
What did I do?
I didn't mean to do that!
I was gonna press a bomb, but okay.
Heal me up.
There's HP.
Ah, ah!
Brother man!
Yeah!
Get float up, bitch!
There's more.
Yo, what the...
The black hole is actually sucking in the projectile.
That's massive.
I need to get closer so my little familiar can help me.
Suck on that.
It healed me.
I'm gonna do it again.
Playing it safe.
Oh, buddy in a box has appeared?
What?
Wait, buddy in a box has appeared?
Does that mean there's a buddy in a box somewhere now?
On this level?
Or is it just like somewhere in the game?
Let's go find it.
It has to mean here now, right?
Oh, nice.
Full HP as well.
Dude, I'm doing great right now.
This is absolutely stellar.
There are no buddies or boxes.
Let's try this one up here.
Nothing.
It's got to be up here then.
It could also be a secret room that I didn't discover yet.
Think about that.
It could be.
I don't want to go in there.
It's going to cost me HP.
Yeah, fuck it.
Go back down to the boss room.
And then we go to the next level.
I'm totally going to win.
Here.
Oh, let's not forget about the ring.
What is it?
I need to see this again.
Oh, shit.
No, wait.
Abba, wait.
This costs energy, right?
So...
And it's space.
Wait, what?
Ah, wait.
It doesn't cost any energy for some reason.
Why is that?
Was there something else?
Smashing and dealing damage.
One of three.
Oh, man.
Being able to remove rocks is actually kind of crazy.
Let's go.
I like...
What is that room?
Why is it gray?
Someone gifted me poop?
This game has a weird obsession with poop.
Depth one.
Okay,
I can do this.
I can't do this.
I need to go this way.
I wonder if I pick out a spiked rock, if that's going to hurt me.
Probably, right?
Oh, my God.
Absolutely unreal.
These enemies are scary as hell.
Oh, wow.
We're going to suck this bomb out of here.
But I don't think it can actually leave.
Even if I get a black hole.
Yeah, it's stuck.
Unfortunately, can I pick this up?
No.
Can I pick anything else up?
This door is going to open when...
When everything is cleared.
That's what I think happens.
Let's try and clear.
What's that?
Brother Bobby, friends till the end.
Friends till the end.
Oh, it's a familiar.
I see him.
He's hidden a little bit.
Conjoined.
Familiar that fires basic tears.
This is so good.
This run is actually so much fun.
Wait a minute.
Did I see a crack in the wall?
There's a crack in the wall here.
I smell a secret, but I don't have a bomb, unfortunately.
Give me the bomb.
Oh my God, Isaac.
You're not looking too great, I gotta say.
Go!
Trying to shoot poop at me.
Black hole, baby!
Yo, the black hole with the Gemini is actually a sick combo.
Because everything gets sucked into the hole, right?
And then the Gemini is on top of it.
And everyone takes damage.
It's the Archon Toilet.
It couldn't be a better combo.
What is this?
Is that a purse?
Backpack?
Something.
What the hell is this?
Recycle?
All the items are changing!
I didn't even see that.
Shit.
I get it.
Whoops.
Okay, well.
Now I know.
You can refresh the items in the shop with that.
Oh man, go this way.
Beautiful.
Oi.
Oh boy, okay, can I...
Oh my God!
It's amazing.
How come the mana bar is full?
Oh no, I used the key.
I didn't mean to.
Crap.
How did I get a key?
I could enter one of these now.
I'm gonna do it.
Oh crap.
Blow it up!
Oh, I wanted to bring it over here so I could blow that up.
Maybe there's stuff in the rocks.
Come on, show me something in there.
Can I break this?
Ah, too bad.
We got a big poop!
So as soon as the black hole happens, I move in with my Gemini.
That's the plan.
Blue fire!
Blue fire cannot be extinguished.
Why?
It burns too hot, I guess.
Whoa.
Black hole?
Gemini, get in there?
Nice.
I actually have a crazy combo going here.
Hey, you like this?
Motherfucker!
Not bad.
Oh, thank you.
This way.
Get him!
What the hell is that?
It's like a little crab creature.
Rotating crab creature.
RCCs.
I don't like those.
I'm unhappy.
Makes me want to cry.
Oh, bombs.
We need those so bad.
I really should be using these rocks, I think.
Rock time!
Uh, take it.
Yeah!
Where you at?
Boom!
Come on.
You gotta actually aim that.
Gemini, you didn't do shit just now.
Come on.
Oh, it doesn't actually hurt me.
Can I pick you up?
Imagine walking around with the gravity stone.
It's gotta be like a secret with these rocks.
Or not.
This way.
Whoa!
Black hole!
We need black hole!
Oh, they all died.
Maybe I killed that master or something.
There was one different, right?
Uh-oh.
Black hole!
Here we go!
Oh, it didn't last very long.
Isaac, you're not doing anything.
I meant to say Gemini.
Lovely.
I feel like I'm being showered with all kinds of things.
Evil tomatoes.
I don't do those.
Okay, so I hear growling.
That's the boss.
Question is, should I go in there yet?
Yes, let's just do it.
I feel good about this.
The cage!
All right!
Oh, he's so fat!
Even gravity doesn't affect...
Oh, wow!
Okay, so we gotta stay at diagonal when he jumps.
Got it.
Oh my goodness!
That's disgusting!
What the fuck, bro?
He's gonna puke?
No?
Oh, he's confused!
Oh no, I'm dying!
Bombs!
Isaac, you need to get in there.
I mean, Gemini, no!
Okay, that works.
Nice!
Oh god, I really gotta stop running into that.
Binky, tears up!
That's good!
That's good, that's good, that's good.
I'm not gonna leave yet.
I'm gonna go back.
I love this part of the soundtrack right now, when everyone's whispering.
And it's just like a cacophony of noises.
It feels good in my ear.
It's delicious.
Gemini and me.
Actually, who's the last one?
Who are you, the blue one?
Brother Bobby.
Right.
So, I can find more of them, I guess.
It says one of three.
We gotta find his brothers, too.
We gotta complete the family.
Oh, easy!
Black hole time!
There it is!
Amazing.
Let's go down here.
Uh-oh.
Close one.
Oh, not these guys!
Get him!
Okay, not bad, not bad.
I hella nailed that.
I got one bomb left, in case I want to look for secrets or something.
This way.
What's up, dude?
Oh, I thought you were a gravity dude!
Oh, no.
I'm taking a lot of damage here for no reason.
I'm so scared when enemies jump.
Getting some good items here, though.
Wow.
I guess as long as I'm diagonal to them, I'm safe.
Yeah.
Coins and a key.
Let's go.
Now, I think I can enter this room up here now.
Everything is cleared.
No!
Unless there is a secret room somewhere that I didn't find.
Right?
Um...
Oh, this looks like a secret.
We got one more shot at this.
Let's do... oh, this one.
Never mind.
I tried, I tried, okay.
Uh, now go left.
No, yeah, yeah, this way.
And now we leave.
This was a good one, though.
We did well.
Get in.
So, how far along are we now?
Oh...
Okay.
We just have a dream of dying by falling?
What potato?
What is that on the wall there?
Oh, yeah.
Wait, it's not arcade.
This is gambling.
It's not arcade.
Oh, I like this.
I'm being ripped off!
It's the worst arcade of all time!
What a rip-off!
Holy crap.
Dude!
I can't see what's happening on the screen.
There's too much.
Wow!
Okay, this is getting very, very difficult.
Black hole!
Get him, Gemini.
What is that sound I'm hearing?
Are they healing?
I don't understand.
Wait, wait, I think I'm healing them.
I don't know how, though, but...
What?
I have no... I think something I do is healing them.
But I also deal damage.
But it's a little imbalanced, so my damage is higher than the healing, so I end up killing them slowly.
I just don't know what the hell is causing this.
Okay, they're not healing anymore.
All right.
Maybe it was these stones, actually.
The fool.
Where journey begins?
Wait, hold on.
If I click this, am I a fool?
Where journey begins.
Is it gonna take me back to the start of this level?
I mean, okay.
What's the point of that?
Maybe to get out of a sticky situation if you're in a bad room, you know?
You don't want to be in there?
Yeah, I can see that, actually.
That makes sense.
Man, we need to heal.
This is not looking good.
Like, holy shit.
Immediately, these guys!
Dude, those projectiles, I can barely see them.
No, it was such a good run, too!
Cheers.
This guy right here, he single-handedly ended this whole run for me.
Because the first time I met him, he took, like, all of my HP, pretty much.
The second time, he killed me.
These are the hardest enemies in the game.
So far.
Ah, but you know what?
Clean slate, you know what that means?
Means potential.
Uh...
Yeah.
Worth it.
Maybe.
Probably not.
Jesus.
That's a lot.
We gotta do...
Like, okay.
Hard is actually kind of hard.
I will say that.
Normal was definitely easy, but they kicked it up a notch on hard here.
I will admit it.
Get these little guys out of here.
I missed Gemini already.
He was such a good partner and team, you know?
Like, everything worked.
Get him out of here.
Nice.
Now, this guy needs to die.
Doesn't seem to mind me being here, actually.
It's just sort of flopping.
Okay, so watch this.
There's a bomb inside that rock.
If I had had the ability to pick up the rock, I wonder if I can just pick up the bomb.
Or if it's going to explode when I do, you know?
More flies!
These are not too bad, actually.
That's easy enough.
These ones are a little annoying.
They're tough.
You can't see which direction they're going to jump.
That's the tough part, right?
They just kind of jump at you.
The boss is here already.
I'm not ready for that yet.
So wait, this pill is worth more than that pill.
Ah, wait, this is a full pill.
You see how this one is half?
I can donate two more and get 50.
There's options.
Has appeared in the basement.
There's options?
Wait, I don't understand what that means.
Has appeared in the basement.
There's options.
Maybe I have the choice between multiple items down here now, somewhere in the basement.
Wow!
What a dodge, though!
Oh, I was doing so well.
Focus!
Okay.
Man, it's not going well.
What's that?
Spider baby.
Spider revenge.
Oh, no.
Spawns three to five blue spiders when taking damage.
I don't like that at all, because I don't want to take damage.
That sounds bad.
Bad item.
Well, I guess we'll go fight the boss now with one HP.
It's Monstro!
We should be able to do this.
This guy's not that tough.
Okay, he's kind of tough.
If I get the little guys out of the way, that should help a lot.
Good.
Wow.
I feel like I'm getting super lucky here.
Ah, so far so good.
Oh my god, that projectile almost hit me.
Okay, it looks like phase two now.
He doesn't do the jump anymore.
Oh, how did that not hit me?
I'm actually confused.
Yeah!
I can't believe I did it.
Eight ball.
Magic eight ball.
Shot speed up.
Oh, Joker.
Um, that's the one that transported me to a weird ass location.
What a nice hat I have on.
Look at that.
Beautiful.
It's a dureg, isn't it?
Let's see here.
Point sixteen shot speed increases chance of planetarium spawning?
What?
Okay, spawns a random card on pickup.
I guess that's how I got the Joker.
Teleport to the devil or angel room.
Angel room?
I'm guessing this is the devil room.
Why won't I get the option to go to the- Ah!
I don't like this room.
I want to get out.
I need to leave.
Let me leave.
Oh, I need to kill this guy or what?
No.
Okay, okay, here we go.
Leave.
Get the hell out of here.
Get the hell out of there.
I want angels, not devils.
Dude, I wonder if at some point Isaac stops crying, you know, and he actually becomes happy.
Because this is just very disturbing.
Like, it's just torment for Isaac, all this.
All these weird dreams he has, you know, it's just all super sad.
And the mom wanting to kill him is super dark.
It's just- it's not good.
I don't feel good about that.
Isaac needs a happy ending.
The Hierophant.
Two prayers for the- I didn't get to read it.
Spawns two soul hearts.
Are those the blue ones?
Aha!
Hierophant.
Nice.
Why do some things have voiceovers and others not?
Isn't that interesting?
Also, what did I even pick up here?
I kind of forgot.
What was that?
Little guy?
Rotten baby?
Following familiar that generates blue flies, got it.
Temperance.
May you be pure in heart.
Now this one, I'm not sure about.
Spawns a blood donation machine.
I don't want that, actually.
Nope.
Maybe there's some kind of way to...
I don't know.
Use that without losing hearts.
What's this?
Well, I don't have money for it anyway.
I don't even want to look when I can't afford it.
Okay.
Ah, this is easy.
He doesn't need spawn the flies.
Thank you.
Spawn them.
And he aims them too.
Or maybe they have free will.
Like he shoots them out and then they just go off on somebody, you know?
I don't know if I should be destroying all this poop.
I think I should be.
Stuff comes out, right?
How do I get in?
Oh, if I had the item that could make me lift rocks, this would be hella...
Oh, he fell in the fire!
Sick.
I want to get in there so bad.
How about, wait, I can.
Load the fuck up.
Stapler?
Sick.
It's the stapler from office space.
Oh, careful, these guys shoot.
I wonder why they shoot and when.
I guess...
Oh my god, stop!
Maybe it's when I get too close, or what?
I'm not sure.
Jesus Christ.
Also, where are these spiders coming from?
Hold on a minute.
Stable's eyesick's left eye shut, causing all shots to be fired from his right eye.
That is disturbing!
But wait a minute, does this mean that I actually have half the attack speed then, if I only shoot from one eye instead of two?
I'm not familiar with the lingo yet, you know?
And the terms.
It doesn't feel like it's slower, but I think I'm good.
Wait, someone's crying!
Is that eyesick crying?
Eyesick?
No, it's these guys!
The enemies are crying.
Oh my god, they're scared of me.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I mean, it's a shitty existence for us all, you know?
My mom wants to kill me, but I also have to kill you.
It's just the name of the game, I'm sorry.
Oh, you can't match up to the do-rag!
Oh, these guys are actually the easiest enemies in the game.
Like, what else, come on.
Wow, they're silver coins.
Is there a gold coin?
That gives me like a hundred, imagine that.
We got ones, tens, and then hundreds would be the next logical step, right?
Also, temperance.
The blood donation machine, right?
I'm not gonna do that yet.
Aha!
Oh, we got a little dude!
It feels like I'm doing a lot of damage.
I kind of like my outfit.
I kind of look like a pretty cool guy, you know?
One eye stables shut with the do-rag.
Oh yeah, I got the drip.
Oh, sh...
Yeah!
Go!
There's one room I didn't explore.
Why did I leave that room like that?
That's just disturbing.
You also have a heart here in case you need it.
Yeah, up here and left.
Wait, I have money!
Does this cost...
It probably costs money to refresh, right?
I'm gonna get this.
I mean, sure.
That's okay.
This one's not gonna do anything because I don't have a battery bar.
There we go.
Now, this door right here...
Wait a minute, I've seen this one before.
Triggers another active item effect chosen at random.
Wait, what?
Wait, triggers another active item effect?
I'm confused by this.
I'm also confused by the two icons on the bottom.
They got a little crown and a cross.
Does that mean there's a chance to do whatever those two icons do?
It's a mystery.
Wait.
Okay, so wait a second.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So this one has a little crown on it.
This one has a enemy icon, a boss icon, treasure chest, and I don't know, some kind of machine.
I don't know what that means.
A compass.
Maybe it's how I can acquire these items.
Let me try this.
Ah, shit!
I didn't mean to use that one, but okay.
Crystal ball.
Huh?
Crystal ball?
Oh, look at this!
There's a room!
Boom!
Praise the Lord!
The crystal ball has foreseen it.
Here it is.
And now we can also test whether or not the door on the very left is going to open.
Because my theory is, when you clear all the rooms, then the door opens.
Is that an enemy?
I'm not sure.
Let's see it.
It's still closed.
Ah, but we haven't defeated the boss yet.
Let's go do that.
It's boss time.
Not here.
I'm actually so confident that this is how it works.
Here we go.
Man, quite the level, huh?
This is a big one.
So, how do I get the mana back?
Or the energy?
There is actually a battery I can buy.
Oh, actually, I think I can pick it up.
Hold on.
I'm going to do that.
I'm going to pick up the battery.
I think that one was free.
Oh, man, what a path.
Here.
Watch this.
Yeah!
Okay.
So, it's just completely mystery when I use this.
I guess that...
I mean, is that good or bad?
Could it spawn something bad for me?
Is it risky to do during the boss?
I'm going to try and use this during the boss.
I feel like that could be fun.
Maybe it spawns, I don't know.
A nuke from orbit and kills the boss immediately.
It's Larry Jr. Okay.
Where's Larry Sr., though?
What is it?
The hourglass.
I have no idea what that is.
Can I read about that?
No, I can't read about it.
Oh, I see.
It slows time down.
You heard that?
It's like, and then they started moving faster.
That is a rotten backpack.
No, it's the belt.
Speed up, right.
No more pants falling down.
Although it would fit with the do-rack.
Just kidding.
Let's go this way now.
In my teams, I actually...
I was part of that movement, you know.
In high school.
I was the kid with the pants, you know.
I know you're not gonna believe that, but...
I was like that.
Okay, let's go.
Man, these enemies are so easy.
They're not even a challenge.
Come on.
Oh no, this is gonna fuck me up.
Wait, why can't I...
extinguish this one?
Okay, I can.
It's just very slow for some reason.
Wait, what's happening?
Wait, I...
Huh?
Where are these spiders coming from?
I don't understand.
Blue spiders are everywhere.
Spawns a random card.
Oh, oh!
Spider baby, of course.
Spawns three to five blue spiders when taking damage.
And I guess I walk into the spikes.
It makes sense.
Now, what is this black card here?
I think I cannot destroy these things right here.
But I'm gonna try anyway.
Yeah, okay.
Fuck.
I don't know.
Kill this guy.
Dude, I killed so much.
Dude, all these spiders.
Wait, this door is open now!
Why is that?
What have I done to open this door?
Oh no, oh no, oh no.
Spiders, help me!
Good.
Oh wait, I shouldn't attack him, because otherwise he's not gonna...
There we go.
That was close.
I think it's always worth it to go in here.
Hold on a minute.
This is gonna give me money, but add a...
And add some kind of bad effect to me, though.
Money equals power.
I mean, that's true.
I get...
Hey, that's awesome.
Okay, let me see.
Is it gonna be like the more money I have, the more damage I do?
Grants a small damage up for each coin health.
Oh man, I like that.
Okay, let's go find some money then.
This could actually be huge.
The problem is, I don't have a lot of HP.
This is really gonna be a disadvantage.
Okay, these little bastards are really annoying.
Oh, I got hit.
Kill him.
Dude, I'm one-shotting them.
Hell yeah.
Distinguished fires.
Oh, at least we need to die at the same time.
What am I doing?
I ran into them.
I can't believe it.
I had everything going for me, and then I just threw it away.
That's the boss.
We're not going in.
Not yet, baby.
Also, let me try this again.
Anarchist...
I was almost running into the bombs, thinking they could heal me, but this is not that run.
I'm so glad I had a last split-second decision not to do it, you know?
Holy shit.
Oh wait, I don't want to use money.
This was dumb.
I need to stockpile money.
That was a mistake.
I can blow these up.
A picture.
Torn photo.
Tears post shot.
That's good.
Oh my gosh, shot speed is crazy up.
It is so up.
I feel so good about killing these guys now.
I don't care if they're crying.
Cry all you want.
Cry, babies.
Conjoined worms!
How much do you want to bet the developer is the one that made the noise going...
He just said it from his microphone, you know?
Oh, my game just lagged.
I thought it was about to crash.
Okay, I'm going to press a button now.
And by the magic of Destiny, I will somehow acquire this heart.
You ready?
Lemon mishap!
I peed my pants.
I actually don't know what happened there.
It looks like P to me, but I could be wrong.
Oh, no.
These guys are going to do that when they die.
So against those, you actually want to be at left, right, up, or down when they die, because they shoot diagonally.
Got it.
I will never forget.
I think this is also pride.
I hate the purple projectiles because I almost can't see them.
The left hand has appeared in the basement.
Oh, yeah, there it is.
So it does appear in the basement.
The left hand path reaps dark souls.
Say that again.
Replaces all chests that spawn with red chests.
Is that good or not?
I don't know if red chests are good.
It must be good, right?
It's not great.
I don't know why it wouldn't be good.
Okay, this guy.
I'm going to blow him up, but I can't get in there.
So I'm not going to blow him up.
Wait, wait.
He has a drawing of a bomb.
Hold on a minute.
I think that these little dudes, they have different drawings, right?
If they have a drawing of a bomb, they're going to eat bombs.
And maybe when you reach a certain threshold, something good happens.
There's also a guy that eats coins.
You give him enough coins, something good happens, right?
I was looking for my mouse with my right hand.
Couldn't find it.
I was like, wait a minute.
This game doesn't require a mouse.
Okay, here we go.
Look!
I'm sorry, dude.
You're not going to get my coins.
I need them.
No, I don't want to step up.
Okay.
I'm going to press a button.
And by the magic, of destiny, I will step on this without taking damage.
Whoa!
Sorry, what?
What's happening?
The nail?
I have no idea.
Did something happen?
I'm going to step on it.
Huh?
Nothing happened.
Okay, I'm leaving.
I mean, wait, I'm no longer a giant demon.
What happened?
Why did that disappear?
Oh, whatever.
I want to leave now.
Take me to the next level.
Man, I kind of want to get more hearts.
Two hearts is just not enough.
Gertie!
Look how big he is!
Wow!
Oh, man, I'm doing a lot of damage.
I should be moving.
Yeah, there we go.
No, I'm an idiot.
Okay, we killed him.
Fruit force.
Uh, breakfast?
More?
Yes!
That is massive.
Is that poop?
What is that gray stuff right there?
Petrified poop.
50% chance for destroyed poops to spawn a pickup.
No, I couldn't take it!
Now they make fun of me because I wear a dress?
Why is that?
These guys have clearly never aired their balls.
The best feeling in the world.
Freedom, baby.
Down this way.
Give me that.
Oh, no.
These things...
Yeah, so we gotta stay at right angles.
Oh, no.
Yeah, look at that.
That was beautiful.
Oh, it's not...
Actually, it's a little bit RNG.
The directions they're shooting.
So you can't always count.
I didn't mean to.
I didn't mean to do that.
Okay, well...
Hey!
Sweetness.
What are these guys?
Okay, these guys always shoot.
Uh...
An up, down, left, and right, I guess.
All right?
Oh, it's Wrath!
The Bomberman!
The Bomberman is such a fun game.
One of the best party games ever made.
You can even push the bombs back to what it seemed.
I'm gonna destroy this one, too.
Ah...
Yes, the more coins we get, the better, right?
This is the coin run.
We need money, baby!
Money!
Yes!
Nice!
Oh my god, the attack speed feels incredible!
This is so, so good!
Nice.
Except I can't hit for shit.
I'm pretty bad at aiming.
It doesn't even bother me anymore that I can't shoot diagonally.
Like, I've gotten used to that.
Gimme this.
So these are gonna drop...
Or like, 50% chance of dropping something, right?
When I destroy them.
By the power of this button, something magical happens.
Celebrity for dummies!
Whoa!
Oh, okay, so it only lasts inside the room you're in when you use it.
Is it always like that for those upgrades or usage items?
I think it may be.
So now I cleared a room and I got more mana.
I think I see how it works now.
I'm not gonna go in there because I'm not gonna use any money.
We are saving money today.
We're making budgets.
All of our expenses are being accounted for.
We will make sure not to overspend on the food.
Our subscriptions.
Everything is taken into account.
Healthy economy.
Damn!
How rude.
I love these glasses.
They're so good.
Oh my god, this is a crazy one.
Wait, they transitioned into a higher being.
They became enlightened.
Not yet.
This way and left.
Okay,
actually that's fine.
What's that?
Lost cork.
This is the size of Isaac's creep puddles?
Uh-huh.
Wait, no, no, I want this instead.
I don't know what that means.
Creep puddles.
Creep puddles could be...
For example, when I had the lemon accident and I was peeing everywhere.
Maybe that's a creep puddle?
I don't know.
Isaac!
The game kit!
Oh, no way!
Oh, that's amazing!
Very cool.
Okay, I gotta start doing that.
Like, every time I enter a room, that is too much fun.
Not that way.
Then again, if I enter the shop, maybe there's a chance that another room is nearby.
Or is there?
Maybe that shop is always a dead end, actually.
I haven't seen a shop with a door inside.
Let's go here.
Can I use this now?
No, I need two charges to use this item.
Beautiful.
Ah, I can't get that.
Cross blast, plus five.
Oh, that sounds fantastic!
Let me see.
Bombs explode in a large cross shape pattern made up of multiple explosions.
That is fantastic.
But I gotta be careful, because I think I can take damage from that myself.
We don't have bomb immunity, unfortunately.
I wish I saw more poop.
Teleport.
I just randomly teleport?
Weird.
Oh my god, I have the Bomberman antenna on.
That's fantastic.
I wonder how the overrides work in this game.
Like, what determines which item gets to be shown on my character if I have both, you know?
That's interesting.
Oh shit, oh shit.
I wanna take out the projectile dudes first, that's for sure.
More coins!
Wait, is that a library?
What's this?
I can choose either the shaft and, you know, the two stones.
Or I can choose a mushroom man.
What should I choose?
Let's do...
Mushroom man.
Anarchist cookbook.
Summon bombs.
Oh no, I don't like that.
What's this?
Book of shadows.
Temporary invisibility!
Okay.
That sounds pretty damn cool.
Gain a damage nullifying shield for 10 seconds?!
What?!
Wait, Bookworm 2 out of 3?
Do I have two books?
How does that work?
I'm gonna do something naughty here.
Wait, Dead Sea Scrolls?
No, no, take this.
I like that one, I like that one.
We're taking this one.
Very cool.
Now, what about that room down there?
Can I finally access that now or what?
I don't think I have understood the mechanics that determines when this room actually opens for me.
It's close now.
Let's go open the shop just to double check this theory.
I'm not gonna buy anything.
Because I need this money.
Let's go!
Whoa, Chub!
Are you happy to see me or what?
Take care of the ads.
Oh wait, uh...
Invisible!
Dude, this is a...
Is this just like a...
How is this not completely broken?
Ten seconds of complete damage?
Know the ability?
Get him!
We did it, we did it.
We can't die now.
Holy crap.
Let's see here.
Right rage, spawn.
Speed and...
Oh, that's good.
We take that.
Now, let's try and get to that room.
Ah, but there is one more room.
There's one more room that we didn't enter up here.
It's gonna cost us a couple hearts.
Actually, one heart in total.
So we take half a damage.
Going into these rooms, I think.
Dude, I'm so fast.
Kill him!
Kill him all!
Okay, so this is a red chest.
Let me see here.
So red chest...
All chests that spawn have been replaced with red chests.
Maybe red chests are just better chests.
Right?
I guess.
Yeah, that makes sense.
Okay, time to check out if this room is open.
It ain't.
That probably means we have a secret room somewhere that we didn't explore yet.
If I am correct with the theory.
Which I very well could not be.
Let's leave!
We're getting out of here.
How far are we?
Okay, a little over halfway there.
Like, what is even this?
They're just making fun of him for being on the toilet?
Curse of the Labyrinth?
What is that?
Can I see it?
I can't see it.
Okay, interesting.
Ah!
Oh.
I'm gonna...
give you bombs.
No way!
Wait, eat more.
Holy cannoli!
Oh, you didn't give me anything there, huh?
Oh, you bastard!
Uh, that's not good.
Hello.
More bombs for you!
Ah, come on now.
No, he ate it.
Okay, well that was a lot of money there.
Very cool.
What is this room even?
Ah, we got items.
I see not.
I'm greedy!
That was really not...
Oh!
This guy wants half my heart, huh?
Should we do it?
It's pretty much like a gamble.
Okay.
Take it.
What am I gonna get?
Nothing?
Again.
No.
One more time.
Oh, you ass...
Dude.
Okay.
I have bad experiences with the heart people.
Not good.
Kill him.
Good stuff.
Poop me.
Hey!
Nice.
I didn't mean to do that.
Oh well.
He's gonna die at the same time.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, there we go.
We got him.
And we're full HP.
Should we go back to the heart, dude?
Let's try it again.
Go!
Give me items!
You know you want to!
Yeah!
A pill!
Balls of steel!
That's right!
I had balls of steel for doing what I just did!
What does it do?
What did I...
What is balls of steel?
I don't know what it is, but okay.
Time to kill some fools.
Oh, they're ascending.
Okay.
Dude, I freaking love this game.
This way.
Kill him.
You know what's crazy?
This game is like so simple.
WASD to move.
Arrow, up, left, down, right.
To shoot.
That's it.
You have two buttons to press items, right?
But it's like super deep despite all that.
It's kind of crazy.
I love that sort of thing.
Okay, we got more bombs.
Get up here.
Wow!
Holy bullet hell!
Ah, no way.
Dude, I lost so much just now.
That was horrible.
Get the poop!
What the...
Kill him!
Like shooting fish in a barrel.
Yeah, come on.
Wonderful.
Take me...
Ooh, what's that?
Proptosis!
Short range, Mega Tears.
It's not that short.
Okay, I guess they become smaller-ous.
I wonder if the size of the tier determines damage as well, or if it's just a visual indicator of how long a range I have, and when they're gonna expire.
Interesting.
Can I see that?
Tears gain a large damage bonus, but have much shorter range.
Tears rapidly shrink in size and...
Okay, there we go.
Answers right there.
I should be reading it before I ask the question.
All right, let's go back here.
I still haven't tried my Bomberman thingy.
Try it now.
Wow!
Get annihilated!
Okay.
I really need the perk that makes me go healing when I take a bomb.
I have no keys.
Also, what is this on the floor there?
There's a drawing of a demon.
Whee!
Oh, wait!
That's a bat...
That's a bat chest!
I didn't like that!
Red chests suck!
I hate the red chests.
Oh, man.
Oh, that was it.
Here we go.
Die!
I ran into it!
I need healing.
This is not going well.
Oh, I got no keys.
I got to find a key.
We got to get in there because those rooms are amazing.
Uh-oh.
Oh, it's a gravity thing.
What do I do here, though?
Huh?
Wait, what?
Do I extinguish fire?
Is that it?
What the...
Why did I take damage?
I'm so confused.
Oh, I mean...
I'm...
Yeah, I mean, come on.
What the fuck?
No, it was such a good run!
No.
Man.
Hold on.
I want to try something.
I want to try the new character I have.
Wait, so...
Hold on a minute.
Three hearts.
Two speeds?
And two attack?
Or what does that mean?
Two boots?
Minus one heart.
Three speed.
Four attack.
Uh-oh.
Wait a minute.
Three black hearts.
I think this means that I can't heal.
And when these hearts are gone, it's over.
I could be wrong.
It's poop.
No, it's mom's wig.
I feel itchy.
Ha ha ha!
What does it do, though?
Yes, mother?
Heals one red heart.
Firing has a chance to spawn blue spiders.
Chance increases with luck.
Huh?
I mean, yeah, of course, chance increases with luck.
That's what luck does.
It increases your chances.
The fool?
Teleport to the starting room of the current floor.
Okay, okay.
I don't understand where I got the card from, but okay.
Oh, so I... oh, no.
Oh, that is a weird mechanism.
I have to sort of commit to a direction when I attack.
Oh,
that's a friendly.
That's just weird.
Okay, it does, like, last a little while.
No.
Yeah, see, now I committed to left, so that's kinda not bad, you know?
So I gotta change.
I'm really underestimating the range on this.
Or overestimating, I should say.
Whoa!
I can go through rocks!
Okay.
Okay, that is massive.
Hello?
Wow.
I didn't even realize that.
I mean, I saw the wings, but I didn't really...
It didn't register, you know, in my mind.
So wait, I can... can I go across the holes now as well?
I bet you I can.
Oh, no, the range!
It's not good enough.
Beautiful.
That's not good.
Look at me!
Wait, can I not just stand here and be immune?
They can't reach me?
Right?
Where are you?
Up here.
Oh, he's gone?
Can I blow up rocks with this?
No.
Oh, my goodness.
Dude, the damage I did was nuts!
I'm in trouble, I'm in trouble!
I'm not, I'm fine.
Kidding.
I'm doing so well.
Oh, wait, I can go across rocks!
I can't even afford kidding.
Wow.
Lucas, I can just... I can play with this guy.
What are you gonna do now?
You're gonna do shit!
It's amazing.
I feel broken.
That's why I can't heal, probably.
I mean, I'm like 99% sure that's what the Blackheart means.
What else could it be, right?
I'm too powerful.
Also, I don't know if I'm playing on normal or hard.
I changed character, maybe that resets difficulty.
It feels kind of hard.
Okay, nice.
Couple keys.
Oh, it's boss time!
Oh, that did a lot of damage.
I killed all these babies in one shot there.
No, I got hit!
No, it's bad!
Oh my god, I'm dying!
It's over.
Nice.
We gotta like, charge up and get in for the kill.
Ah, bad, bad direction there.
Okay, now we go.
Yeah!
Stuy!
Damage plus range up.
Oh!
I don't feel the damage.
Oh no, I can't heal.
Okay, so I was right.
Shit.
Let's go back.
Uh, I guess there is a way to heal, actually, because you can find Blackhearts, no?
We saw that before.
Yeah.
Yeah, actually.
Yeah, we can heal, but it's just more rare.
Definitely.
Go this way.
Poop!
Spit on that poop.
Uh, this way.
What the?
Ugh!
I hate that design!
Get away from me.
Ugh.
Nasty.
Hate that stuff.
That's a very seductive bomb right there, but I'm gonna...
Put in a couple coins there.
Let me see here.
Oh yeah, look, even this change is here.
Hold.
Bombs and items, right.
Okay, time to move on.
Okay, this character is really fun.
I like being able to just traverse across rocks.
That is crazy.
I understand why I have Blackhearts now.
It makes a lot of sense.
I think I haven't really...
Oh, I have golden tears as well.
It's beautiful.
Okay, let's go.
Oh man, even Azazel is crying.
I wonder if this is just another version of Isaac, you know?
Like, is this just his emo phase, you know?
Could be.
A mushroom!
Odd mushroom.
HP plus damage up.
Speed down.
Okay, that wasn't a lot of speed though.
That's fine, I guess.
Actually, that could be a problem.
Let's see here.
Fun guy.
Nice.
Nice pun.
That's a lot of extra damage in range, isn't it?
Like, we are not messing around with that.
Let me see.
Doesn't feel like that much.
Wait, my attacks go through stones?
They must be, right?
Because I'm flying.
Okay, yeah, this is sick.
This is actually sick.
Oh, god.
That was risky.
The world!
Open your eyes and see.
That sounds cool.
Ah, that's awesome!
Okay, okay.
So, we got a little secret right down here.
Wait, there's a pill.
I can fly to it!
Speed up!
Hey, we got the speed back, baby!
I love it.
All right, this is actually fantastic.
I really like this character.
This is great.
Oh, I can just fly across?
I'm an idiot.
No, I can't.
I didn't mean to do that just now.
Orphan Socks.
What kind of a fucking name is that for an item?
A lot of speed.
Plus two Soul Hor- Oh, cool.
Allows walking on ground hazards like spikes and creep without taking damage?
Well, I'm flying anyway, so who cares?
Does not prevent damage from curse room doors or sacrifice spikes.
Got it.
Amazing.
What is that?
Is that a bucket?
No, that's a pill.
Should we be pilling?
Let's do it.
Pill me!
Placebo.
It's a pill mimic.
Wait, what?
Wait a minute.
Triggers the effect of the pill held without consuming it.
Variable charge based on the last pill copies.
Ah, that's cool.
So if I hold the pill in the bottom right of the screen, I can keep pilling like crazy.
So if I find a pill that gives me speed, I can become like Mega Man speed.
I don't know if Mega Man runs fast.
No, that's Sonic, right?
But you know what I mean?
I'm gonna become Mega.
Don't confuse that with MAGA.
That's different.
Let's Mega Seizel godly again, you know?
He needs to be godly, man.
Come here.
Actually, we are kind of godly.
We have wings and shit.
Oh my god, I'm hiding behind the rocks.
I'm broken.
It's actually broken.
Holy crap.
The potential.
The potential?
Wow.
I need more pills.
There's a pill in here.
Oh yeah, there's a pill in here.
Pheromones?
Is that good?
I don't know what I just did.
I'm actually so confused right now.
I put on pheromones and then I did something else, and now my mana is gone.
I don't get it.
Oh no.
What is that poop?
It's a cake poop.
Rainbow poop.
Huh?
I don't know what that did.
You unlocked Lazarus.
That's a character.
Oh, I'm actually already excited for that.
Hell yeah.
What's this?
Ah, do I go in there?
It's going to consume blue hearts.
I feel like my hearts are super valuable with this character.
I can't just willy-nilly throw that away, you know?
Nah.
I'm going to keep exploring.
Oh, this guy just died for some reason.
Like, I didn't even touch him.
What's up with that?
Maybe there's an item that lets me recharge this, or charge up my laser faster, because that's kind of a bottleneck for me right now.
Wait a sec.
Hold on.
Orphan.
And I was walking on ground hazards like spikes without...
Right now.
What?
What do you mean?
You're lying!
Bullshit!
What the fuck is that?
I was promised something, and I didn't get it.
It's actually unreal.
Like, I'm flying, and I have the freaking socks on.
Oh, I got flies now.
Nice.
Kill him!
Laser time!
Boink!
You...
Oh man, that is cool.
Oh, the power!
I'm trying not to let it get to my head.
It's difficult, but I'm trying.
Dude, how am I ever gonna go back to Isaac?
When I've seen the power of flying?
BFF?
I don't have any money.
Fine, donate.
Yes, we'll do it.
Boom!
Now we go up to the boss.
We have almost no HP.
This is gonna be interesting.
I hope there's gonna be a boss where I can sort of abuse the fact that I'm flying.
Is that even gonna be a thing?
We'll see.
Can I charge up before I go in?
Probably not.
Garglings?
Oh no.
I'm not ready for this level of scrutiny!
Wow, that was quick!
You unlocked the cellar!
Okay.
Dinner?
Looks like dog food.
That doesn't look good.
Yes, mother.
Plus one health.
Heals one.
Oh, wait, wait a minute.
We have two red hearts?!
Are we not already kinda...
Like, really strong because of that?
That seems kinda good.
Like, really good.
Um...
Wait, wait, wait.
These fires are gonna fuck me.
We're not gonna risk it.
Take him out!
Uh, okay, so hold on.
I don't think I'm gonna take any of this.
I feel like I value my red hearts a lot right now, especially on this character.
Yeah, I'm leaving.
Let's go.
Yeah, no more toilet paper.
Maybe that's a bad sign.
Perhaps these videos actually kinda forebode something, you know?
Why is this door open?!
Wait a second.
I think I know what's happening.
We went to, uh, the Devil Realm, right?
We chose not to participate.
We did not join in on the fun, right?
So maybe that's why this door's open now.
Uh-oh.
Yeah!
Kill them all!
Nice.
Whoa!
Kill them!
Nice!
I'm so fast!
Ah, you know what?
I hate about this, though.
I hate the fact that my red hearts are to the left and not to the right of my black hearts.
You know what I mean?
You probably see why that is.
But yeah, it's okay.
Maybe there's a way to reverse that.
Maybe there's an item that says reverse, and then your heart's reverse or something.
Uh-oh!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
You know what I mean?
Kill them.
I actually was about to say something profound, but then I realized it wasn't profound at all.
And I had to stop myself halfway through, so I just decided to, you know, just garble some words.
And pass it off as profound wisdom.
No, thanks.
I'm wrong- I'm wrongly configured!
I'm okay now.
The configuration is bad!
Okay, we're good.
Uh, no thanks.
Not going in there.
I value my hearts, thank you very much.
Come on.
Man, why am I always in the wrong configuration?
There we go.
Oh, wait, I can- I can actually just go anywhere.
It is broken as hell.
I'm rich!
What's the- oh, wait, they can fly too!
Ah, ha, ha!
You know your judo well!
One of me, one of me.
No!
That was dumb!
I wasted a heart.
Oh, god.
A caisel- wait, isn't a caisel the name of an angel?
That's like an angel name, isn't it?
But why am I all, like, demon-looking?
This does not look like an angel to me.
Oh, wait, a caisel is probably like a demon angel.
From the underworld or something, right?
He's one of the bad guys.
Yeah, yeah, that's it, that's it.
That's what it is.
I'm actually a bad guy!
What if I am one of the kids at school that bullied Isaac?
Dude, I am not Isaac!
I'm playing the bad guy!
That's probably what's happening here.
And by probably, I mean there's a 17.9% chance.
Two flies?
Wait, this is that good one.
Money time.
Let's fuck it.
Dude, this is gonna be nuts.
We're gonna make such a crazy build here.
Golden poop?
Tell me it's money.
This is crazy!
Wow!
Got him!
Oh wait, no, no, I understand these guys now.
You kill them once and then they leave a little corpse behind.
You kill that corpse, they're gone forever.
They don't need to die at the same time.
I misunderstood.
I have now been rectified.
Sir!
It's not good.
I lost an HP.
More money for me.
I'm a glass cannon right now.
That's what I am.
Cool.
I'm actually rich, I have 32 monies.
Hey, they can't reach me while I'm standing here.
I wonder if Azazel is like the next character you always unlock.
Or maybe I got lucky by, I don't know, unlocking him by doing something special.
I actually have no idea.
Maybe there is like a natural progression.
Maybe after you maybe have five runs or something, successful or not, you unlock a new character, you know?
Uh, boss time!
Let's go!
It's Gertie Jr., okay.
Dude, the damage I do is not...
Uh-oh, uh-oh, uh-oh.
I'm dead!
I'm okay.
Oh my god.
Stem cells.
Yeah!
Why is it, why are the trumpets?
It's like a quarter of a heart that is now white, and the trumpets go off as if I found, I don't know, Jesus himself, ready to mingle, you know?
I don't get it.
I don't, I don't get it.
Wait, it's gone now!
Wait, why do I have four hearts?
I am so confused.
Didn't I just have two hearts and then I got the upgrade?
That gave me, like, an extra heart and then I found the white stuff that made the heart, like, have a quarter of the white stuff.
I'm so confused.
Maybe it didn't count correctly.
Come here.
Doesn't this look like an elevator?
Wait a minute.
No, never mind.
A blue guy.
Dude, I have yet to meet an enemy that I don't immediately one-shot with his laser.
It is that strong.
Boom!
Didn't expect that, did you now?
This is like me using a sting against a shot hit.
No chance.
Yeah!
Oh, I'm starting to develop new ways of playing with the laser.
The fact that I can move around so much with it afterwards, you know, it's kind of huge.
You!
Yeah, hunt him down.
Boom!
I am so fast!
What the fuck?
Dude, my legs are vibrating because I'm so happy about my situation right now.
Oh no!
I take it back.
This was a good start and now it's not so good.
And boom!
Never peek your head, not against me.
Yo!
Yeah, yeah, they don't have to die at the same time.
That was a mistake there.
Wait, you can't reach me.
Look at this!
Broke!
That is actually insane.
I need to utilize that way more.
That was crazy.
Oh wait, the flies can reach me though.
Boom!
I need healing.
Kill me.
Dude, I think I just realized what the little white heart did.
I think when you put it on, if you make it to the end of the level without taking damage, you get a new heart.
I had everything going for me.
I was rich.
I had bombs up the wazoo.
I had five keys.
I didn't even realize.
I was on track to become world star.
As the kids say.
And I messed it up.
I did.
I threw it out the window.
Hold on a minute.
I need to see something.
What's this?
Lazarus.
That's the guy that came back from the dead.
But he had to die first.
He has minus five poops?
What does that mean?
Oh wait, that's win streak.
I have no wins!
I'm doing so bad.
Also, it's always on hard, no matter what character I choose.
I like Azazel a lot.
This is my favorite character so far.
Lazarus, three hearts, two boots, two attack.
Oh, that's the same as Isaac.
So there's got to be like some kind of difference though.
That is not shown here, you know?
Dope.
But that's it for now.
Guys, this is difficult.
Very difficult.
I definitely underestimated the difficulty at first.
Like, you know, when you start into the game, you shoot the projectiles, you know, the enemies are kind of slow.
I was like, okay.
I knew it was going to get harder, of course.
But I wasn't prepared for how much harder.
I feel like I kind of nailed the game on normal though.
Like, I showed it who's boss, you know?
Then I went on hard and the reverse happened.
First impression, I like it.
It's a great game.
I can already see lots of fun.
Like, when I saw the list of items, I still can't believe it.
Because I feel like when I walk through these levels, I'm kind of finding a lot of the same items.
So how on earth are there that many items?
That's nuts.
Right?
Yeah, I noticed that, Yudhuri.
All kinds of things are affected by it.
I feel like also just the number of enemies has changed on hard.
But yeah, guys, don't spoil anything.
I see some messages being deleted.
Thank you, Frank.
Let me figure it out on my own.
Yeah, it is kind of addicting.
I kind of just want to go again and again.
But now I'm really hungry.
Oh, and this music is really good.
This is actually such a good track.
It's super hard.
What's next?
Next is me eating dinner.
And the next stream, we're gonna play Ocarina...
Not Ocarina of Time.
Majora's Mask.
I think I'm getting close to the end there.
And then after that, we're gonna do more icing, of course.
We're going for the 1k hours?
It depends how much fun I'm having.
If I'm still having fun in a thousand hours, yeah, of course.
But if not, then no.
It's very simple.
I'm glad you guys are enjoying the ice extreme.
Can you say hi to Meteor Town?
Hi Meteor Town.
What is that?
Is that a band?
Sounds like a band to me.
At some point, you must start using mods.
Why?
People kept saying that about Minecraft as well, and I had plenty of fun.
But we'll see.
I'm gonna start playing the game as it is, though.
See how long I get with that.
What's up, Hive?
Happy birthday.
We love eyesack?
I mean, there's definitely an obsession with eyes in this game.
I was horrified to read about the scooper scooping out his own eye.
Like that is just messed up.
There's one cosmetic mod everyone uses that just adds a little dance when you find good items.
I feel like that is not good, though.
Because that immediately tells me what items are good and which ones aren't.
And I kind of want to figure that out on my own.
Am I crazy?
That sounds like a huge spoiler of a mod.
Like, what the fuck?
But maybe later, when I've seen all the items, then we can do it.
But that sounds like a lot of fun, actually.
It makes your character dance.
Yeah.
Does any of you actually have all the items in the game?
Is it hard to get to?
How's your kitty doing?
She's doing great.
I'm actually about to feed her.
Because we eat dinner together these days.
She's going to get wet food tonight, so she's always excited for that.
A friend of mine nearly has all of them.
Oh, a lot of you are saying yes.
Ooh, wow.
Okay.
I imagine that requires a lot of commitment.
Some unlocks are almost impossible without the wiki.
I imagine so.
You get an achievement if you unlock everything?
I would sure hope so!
Like, imagine if you didn't.
You got everything now.
Go outside.
That's the only message you get.
I mean, I would demand an achievement, at least.
Even though I don't really care about achievements.
Even I would demand an achievement, if I got all the items.
Intrinsic joy of watching the number go up, Stanley Parable style.
Wait, what do you mean Stanley Parable style?
And try not to spoil anything from Stanley Parable now, but watching the number go up.
Maybe you're talking about gathering certain things in that game.
It's probably about your meaning, right?
What's your favorite item so far?
It's the money glasses!
Mostly because I love how they look.
They are so good.
I just love looking at Isaac when he has them on.
Hell yeah.
I wanna become rich and successful in the Isaac world.
Wait, it's difficult.
It's a difficult game.
Noita?
Let me think.
What is actually harder?
Noita or this so far?
I would say Noita so far, but I haven't really played that much of this game, right?
Noita is definitely...
That game can punish you without any warning at all.
You're dead, you know?
That is rough.
Doesn't feel like that's the case here.
Like, in that last run, I definitely messed it up bad.
I was totally on autopilot, just, you know, speaking, not really paying attention.
It's a childhood game for you and your brother.
Awesome.
I'm glad you guys are enjoying this, because I am as well.
That's when it really happens, you know?
When you guys are enjoying it and I'm enjoying it.
That's when the symbiosis really hits peak.
It doesn't get better than that.
Even Jackie wanted to play this game.
I was taking a break, and then when I came back, Jackie was sitting here, you know?
In front of the microphone, like, I'm playing now.
And I'm picking a Zazel.
I'm her brother.
Oh, really?
Oh, shit.
Well, there you go.
That was so fun.
Yeah, wasn't it?
And you know what the best part is?
Every single run I've done has felt so different, too.
That one crazy run I had, where I had this weird-ass fucking laser circle.
Like, what the shit is that?
Like, if I even hadn't gotten that today, there's no way in hell I would have predicted that such an item would exist.
You know?
Like, what the...
That's awesome.
If you get 100% achievement in less than 100 additional hours, then you get the speedrun world record.
Okay, so let's try and go for that, then.
That sounds good.
Except I'm idling in the menu now.
It's probably a bad idea, huh, if I want to get that.
Or maybe it's, like, in-game time when you're in a run, I don't know.
Are people actually speedrunning, like, getting all the items?
Is that a thing?
Why am I asking?
Of course it's a thing.
People are insane.
There's this guy that played all the Souls games.
Sekido, Elden Ring, everything.
Without dying once.
Like, oh my god.
That is just next level of commitment and dedication, right?
112 hours is current record.
But you can't even stay awake for that long.
It's gotta be, like, over multiple streams, otherwise that is just actually a health hazard.
Of course it's over multiple streams.
There's no way someone is doing that straight up in one go.
That's crazy.
Steeping time included in the speedrun.
Wait, are you kidding or are you serious?
Oh, you're kidding, okay.
You're kidding, okay, I see.
I mean, if that was a thing, I would honestly watch it.
I think that could be entertaining in its own way.
Guys, I'm outta here.
Thank you all for joining me on this.
This was a lot of fun.
This is a great game.
How come every single game you guys end up voting for that always wins the vote always has the best music?
It has always, always been a 100% thing with that.
Maybe with the exception of one game.
You know which one.
But all the others, like, the music just slaps.
It's almost like there's a correlation between how good a game is and how good the music in that game is.
Music means so much in a game.
It matters so much.
Who puts the games on the vote list?
Some guy named Daniel.
I don't even know him.
Like, he just emails me like, these are the games.
And I'm like, okay, I put them on the list, right?
I don't question it, I just do it.
So yeah.
I'm kidding, of course.
It's me, I pick the games.
Come on now.
Anyway, guys, thanks for watching and subscribing and hanging out with me.
Having fun with this?
Because I sure had a lot of fun.
I will see you in the next stream slash video, alright?
Have a wonderful Saturday.
And don't you dare have a bad Sunday.
I'll see you, bye-bye.